It's my distinct honor to once again administer the oath to our second panel of the first
day of the citizen's hearing.
This panel will run until approximately 1245.
We'll have opening statements of 10 to 15 minutes maximum and then questions of five
to seven minutes.
So Mr. Gillin, you've already shared the oath.
So it's your option whether to do it again, but if the rest of the panel could repeat
after me.
I do hereby affirm that I will tell the truth and nothing but the truth to the members of
this committee today.
Thank you.
We are for the second time this morning honored to begin with Mr. Dolman.
My goodness.
Thank you, esteemed members of the committee, and I will keep my remarks a little more mercifully
brief than the last time, and I apologize for not having this statement for you.
I will provide that for you for the record before we're done here.
I just want to point out that researchers of UFO phenomenon have long argued with each
other over many aspects of this phenomenon, but one conclusion that I think all of us
share, at least serious research, is that the UFOs have become a central, although covert,
but essential component of U.S. history in the modern era and indeed of world history.
But as everyone knows, you can't have much of a history that is a reliable, factually
based history without access to documents, and it's the documents of the past that enable
us in the present to try to puzzle through the complexities and to find solid ground,
as it were.
And yet it's easy for us to forget that access to most of the key UFO documents we now have
came to us by way of historical accident, and it happened to be a fleeting one at that.
All through the 1940s and 1950s and 1960s and well into the 1970s, there were many thousands
of classified pages written about UFOs.
Of course the general public didn't know about this, and neither, it appears, did many or
maybe even most members of Congress.
But then came the end of the war in Vietnam and, of course, Watergate.
And this was a certain key moment in American history, a moment in which the United States
Congress investigated the intelligence community, for example, and when it reopened the investigation
of the assassination of President John F. Kennedy and Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and
others.
And it was a moment in which Congress dramatically strengthened the United States Freedom of
Information Act, enabling U.S. citizens to petition their government for documents not
merely relating to them personally but to the nation in terms of broad issues of public
policy.
Well, little did members of Congress realize that of all subsequent Freedom of Information
Act requests, the most popular category would be related to UFOs.
And indeed, during the late 1970s, over 10,000 pages of documents relating to UFOs were released.
The party lasted until about 1982 when a presidential order by Ronald Reagan made FOIA substantially
less user friendly and did not require many agencies to reply in a timely manner at all.
The result was a major ballooning in costs to those people making requests.
So the glory era of Freedom of Information documents, at least pertaining to UFOs, came
to an end.
To this day, more than half of all U.S. declassified UFO documents come from that period of time,
over 30 years ago.
Great for the Carter administration, shame on the subsequent ones.
And yet we remain fortunate, I think, because the documents that we have, thank goodness,
give us at least enough.
They give us enough of a history to hold on to.
They give us enough solid ground.
And their aggregate message is startlingly clear.
UFOs have been the subject not merely of interest to our nation's military and intelligence
community, but at times a subject of concern and even alarm.
But how could it be otherwise when we have report after report of violations of sensitive
airspace by objects that defy any logical or conventional explanation, whether the scene
was Los Alamos during 1948 and 1949, or Oak Ridge Laboratories from 1948 through much
of the 1950s, or the many military bases during the 50s, 60s, and 70s that reported such events.
The question remains, how could this not be a matter of grave concern to those parties
responsible for maintaining the integrity of their airspace?
And not surprisingly, we find the tone of their memos and requests for information to
be appropriate to the matter at hand.
Here's one CIA memo from 1949, puts the matter in this very succinct way, quote, "Information
is desired if this was some new or experimental aircraft or for any explanation whatsoever."
And these statements are, in fact, typical.
And the situation became so stressful to the CIA and elsewhere that on December 2nd, 1952,
this is right at the very end of the Truman presidency, the CIA's chief of scientific
intelligence, H. Marshall Chadwell, wrote a classified memo to his boss, that was the
director of the CIA, Walter Betel Smith.
And a key paragraph in this memo is as follows.
At this time, the reports of incidents convince us that there is something going on that must
have immediate attention.
Sightings of unexplained objects at great altitudes and traveling at high speeds in
the vicinity of major U.S. defense installations are of such nature that they are not attributable
to natural phenomena or known types of aerial vehicles, end quote.
I think this is a statement that bears very close scrutiny.
Here is yet another comment by a high-level U.S. official that UFOs were real, probably
artificial, probably intelligently operated, and not apparently ours.
And nor was there serious consideration that these were Soviet.
So I would ask, if not American, if not Soviet, if not natural phenomena, and if they appeared
to be technological and under intelligent control, well, we begin to run out of viable
options.
It is access to documents such as these that enable us to know with certainty that UFOs
were a matter of serious concern to individuals at the highest levels of U.S. national security.
I would want to stress that I don't think any of the formally declassified documents
we have by themselves prove that UFOs are ET.
I don't think any of them do.
But I would argue that if you take the top 50, even the top 10, that they make a very
powerful case, I would say not even a matter of speculation but a matter of proof that
the phenomenon was considered real by the responsible members of our national security
community.
That I would say is not a matter of debate or speculation.
And really the questions that we need to ask is why were they considering it, and did they
form any opinions themselves?
Getting at that answer is a little more difficult.
But nonetheless, the bottom line is these documents do prove this.
And it's important because all of these levels of concern were consistently voiced within
the classified world, but they were not given out publicly all through the '40s and '50s.
Right up to our own era, the formal public statements are always the same, that there's
nothing to this, that it may be interesting or may not, but we're not interested in it.
We don't do UFOs.
And fortunately, as the historical accident of freedom of information turned out, those
documents proved the lie to those statements of denial.
So today, official pronouncements about UFOs by the government and military follows the
exact same tone.
There's really no difference between what they say now and what they said 50 years ago,
except they're a little less insulting about it.
Like in the early years, there were a number of statements that talked about people just
kind of being crazy, psychopathological, that you don't hear that anymore.
But other than that, it's really the same type of tone.
Unfortunately, though, that we don't have the kind of access to classified information
on UFOs as we once briefly obtained in the past.
And yet, enough genuine and recent UFO accounts have become known to us, many of which involve
US military, that we can see that very little has changed.
Something important is happening behind the veil of the classified world.
My question to you is, how long will current members of Congress and the public at large
be content to roll over and be spoon-fed nonsense by responsible officials when in fact they
deserve the truth?
Thank you.
Good afternoon, or good morning, distinguished members and panelists of the Citizen Hearing
on Unidentified Flying Objects, UFOs.
My name is Jose Antonio Neus, and I'm a Chilean-American journalist who has been actively involved
in covering the mystery of UFOs and its hypothesis of extraterrestrial ET origin.
Other theories are also possible and should be considered for the past 37 years.
My very first article on this topic was published in a small New York newspaper on July 4, 1977,
coinciding with the beginning of my professional career as a journalist in the United States.
I was born in this country, but my family was from Chile.
My father worked for several years in the United Nations in the early formative years
of this international body, during which time I was born in New York in 1950.
After graduating from high school in Santiago in 1969, I went to Europe and took a semester
on French language and civilization at the Sorbonne University in Paris, and later studied
journalism at the University of Chile in Santiago.
I worked for a while as a science journalist for a weekly magazine in Santiago and also
wrote regularly for a daily newspaper in the mid-70s, where I was one of the first journalists
in Chile to cover ecological or green issues on a regular basis.
This was, however, a period of great turmoil in Chile following the military coup of September
11, 1973, the first time that fateful date shows up in modern history.
I might add, so I took the decision to claim my U.S. citizenship and move to this country
where I have lived ever since.
First in the Washington, D.C. area, then New York for some 25 years, back to the Beltway
where I lived in Northern Virginia for about three years, and now the Phoenix, Arizona
area where I moved in 2009 after I was hired to work as a full-time paid journalist and
editor of Open Minds magazine and also a writer for our website, Open Minds.TV, and other
production and research activities in ufology for the company Open Minds Production.
The subject of UFOs is a contentious one where many different views and attitudes coexist,
sometimes in a friendly manner, sometimes in a more atrimonious way.
But there is no doubt in my mind that there is at least one conclusion we can and should
all agree, UFOs are definitely a global phenomenon.
They're cited visually, on film, and on radar, reported, investigated sometimes officially,
sometimes by private organizations, and covered by both the local and international media
all over the world.
It doesn't really matter what is the culture, language, religion, ethnic origin, and level
of development and technological capabilities of a country.
UFOs have been reported everywhere, from Alaska to Chile and Argentina and the Americas, all
over Europe, Asia, the Middle East, Africa, Australia, and the oceans.
There are well-documented cases in many parts of the world, including Brazil, France, Iran,
Russia, Zimbabwe, New Zealand, and many other countries.
Regardless of what turns out to be the final origin of this mystery, it has a great potential
of unifying the different and often divided parts of our world.
The reason is simple.
No matter how big our ideological, religious, or cultural differences are, we would all
tend to unite in the face of an unknown, possibly extraterrestrial presence.
It is for this reason that some efforts have been made over the years to bring the subject
to the attention of the United Nations Organization.
This international body, despite its flaws, is the only organization that truly represents
all the nations of the world, and so it seems to be the logical place where this issue could
be dealt with in a global, formal, and legal manner.
I will outline briefly the history of UFOs at the United Nations, a subject that I know
very well firsthand since I personally attended as a journalist the famous historical UFO
hearing before the UN Special Political Committee on November 27, 1978.
This was the result of a two-year lobbying effort by Sir Eric Gehry, the Prime Minister
of Grenada, a small Caribbean island which had gained independence from Great Britain
in 1978.
I'm submitting for the record a long article detailing the history of UFOs at the UN, which
I published in the third issue of Open Minds Magazine in 2010.
Grenada's UFO proposal was first raised officially by Prime Minister Gehry and Grenada's UN Ambassador
Wellington Friday at a meeting of the UN General Assembly Special Political Committee on November
28, 1977.
Grenada proposed the, quote, "establishment of an agency or a department of the United
Nations for undertaking, coordinating, and disseminating the results of research into
unidentified flying objects, UFOs, and related phenomena."
Grenada made further statements on November 30 and December 6, 1977.
In an earlier speech in October, Prime Minister Gehry disclosed his own sighting, quote, "I
have myself seen an unidentified flying object, and I have been totally overwhelmed by what
I have seen."
As a result of all this effort, on December 13, 1977, the General Assembly adopted decision
32/424, which acknowledged the draft resolution submitted by Grenada.
Secretary General Kurt Baalheim duly forwarded decision 32/424 to the member states by a
note verbal on March 13, 1978.
However, only three governments responded, India, Luxembourg, and Seychelles, and only
two specialized agencies, International Civil Aviation Organization and UNESCO, replied
with a flat, "No comments to offer."
On the 3rd, Grenada launched a new offensive in 1978 with the help of one of the original
NASA astronauts, Gordon Cooper, among others.
A group of recognized experts was assembled by Gehry to testify at a hearing before the
Special Political Committee on November 27, 1978, which became the high point of the Grenada
initiative.
Besides Sir Eric Gehry and Ambassador Friday, who was now Grenada's Minister of Education,
the hearing included testimony by astronomer Dr. J. Alan Hynek, the former scientific
consultant for the U.S. Air Force Project Blue Book, who went on to found the Center
for UFO Studies, CUFOS; Dr. Jacques Vallee, Stanton Friedman, who was present at the citizen
hearing; and a firsthand witness account by Lieutenant Colonel Lawrence Coyne of the U.S.
Army Reserve on the famous October 18, 1973, UFO helicopter near collision in Ohio; a letter
of endorsement by astronaut Gordon Cooper, who was then working for the Walt Disney Company
as Vice President of Research and Development for Epcot, was read into the record.
Besides mentioning his own sighting and views on UFOs, Cooper wrote that, "We need to have
a top-level coordinated program to scientifically collect and analyze data from all over Earth
concerning any type of encounter, and to determine how best to interface with these visitors
in a friendly fashion."
At a meeting of the UN General Assembly on December 18, 1978, Decision 33/426 was adopted
with the same heading to the previous Decision 32/424, establishment of an agency or a Department
of the United Nations for undertaking, coordinating, and disseminating the results of research
into unidentified flying objects and related phenomena."
The Grenada Initiative was gradually opening the door to UFOs at the UN, but unfortunately
the effort came to an abrupt halt when the Gary government was overthrown by a Marxist
revolution led by Maurice Bishop of the New Jewel movement in March 1979.
Ironically, Gary was in New York to meet with Kurt Valheim regarding Decision 33/426 when
the coup took place.
Some minor efforts to rekindle the UFO initiative at the United Nations were attempted by civilian
investigators since the Grenada coup of 1979, but with no success whatsoever, because only
sovereign member country can bring this issue back officially to the UN, and no government
has done so since the Grenada Initiative of the late 70s.
The good news, however, is that we don't have to reinvent the wheel.
The UN Decisions 32/424 and 33/426 are already on the books and could be revived if there
was political will.
In closing these opening remarks, I want to make a few important points.
While it's true that the majority of UFO sightings have mundane explanations, a fact recognized
by most competent investigators and scientists, if you really study with an open mind the
extensive data bank of UFO cases collected worldwide during the last six decades, you
will find a small percentage of truly puzzling incidents that defy any conventional explanation.
The prevailing view among most researchers and the media is that these cases have an
ET origin, but this is not the only explanation.
Other theories, including interdimensional or multiple universes, have also been advanced.
Even time travel has been proposed.
In other words, UFOs would be our own devices from the future coming back in time for unknown
reasons.
I realize all this sounds like science fiction, but think for a minute.
Didn't you see people talking to each other at huge distances while viewing themselves
on a screen in lots of sci-fi movies from the 50s and 60s?
Well, this happens now every day through Skype and the internet.
Similar examples can be multiplied at infinitum.
What is important is to look at all the data without any preconceived ideas or beliefs.
The late Dr. Hynek used to say that UFOs were likely signaling the next scientific revolution.
But we will never get there if we don't study the phenomenon in a truly comprehensive and
unbiased way, and I might add, with the proper resources to do so.
The political implications, or exopolitical as it's now referred, are even bigger.
The alien can become a catalyst to unify the peoples of Earth to realize that mankind must
grow way beyond our current limitations if we are going to survive and prosper in the
future.
Many believe that open contact will never happen in an open way unless mankind's level
of consciousness makes a significant jump.
Let me finish with an appropriate quote from Shakespeare's Hamlet, "There are more things
in heaven and earth, Horatio, that are dreamt in your philosophy."
Thank you very much.
Good morning.
Good morning, congressmen and congressmen and Senator Ravel.
My name is Dan Sheehan.
I am general counsel for the committee.
I've been asked to speak briefly here today to address a few different instances that
have occurred in my career as an attorney that bear upon this particular subject that
have led to me ending up being general counsel.
I was also general counsel for the original disclosure conference that we had in 2001.
So I've been around for a while on this particular area and it arose because I was chief counsel
for the United States Jesuit headquarters in Washington, D.C. here back in 1976 when President
Carter was elected president.
And immediately after his election in November of 1976, President Carter called into his
office the then central intelligence agency director, who was George H.W. Bush.
And President Carter asked to be briefed by the director of central intelligence on the
issue of UFOs.
And in that meeting, CIA Director Bush asked the president-elect if the president-elect
would leave him in as the central intelligence agency director and that he would promise
that he would never run for political office in his life if Carter would agree to keep
him in as the director of the CIA.
Bush wanted to, at that time, become more or less like J. Edgar Hoover had become at
the FBI, that he would remain, that it would be above politics, that he would remain in
that position.
President Carter reiterated his request for the UFO information, saying that he had his
own person in mind to be the director of the central intelligence agency, which happened
to be Teddy Sorensen at the time.
And Bush at that time then refused to provide the information to him, saying that he did
not have adequate clearances, he was not the president yet, and that he should ask his
own central intelligence agency director for that.
But if he wanted to have the information ahead of time, that what he could do is he could
contact the Science and Technology Committee of the House of Representatives, and they
had an ongoing relationship with the Science and Technology Division of the Congressional
Research Service that could go about getting things declassified to show him.
That is what generated the request from the Congressional Research Service to me as the
general counsel for the Jesuit headquarters in the United States, asking if I could gain
access to the Vatican Library to obtain the information that the Vatican has in its library
in its classified sections to deliver to the president for his review.
I did that.
I contacted the Jesuit, who happens to be the head of the Vatican Library, requesting
this information.
And much to my surprise, I was denied information.
I wrote a second letter to them saying, "Look, I guess you must not know who we are here.
This is the Jesuit headquarters in the United States.
We have 10 provinces here in the United States, more than any other country in the world,
and we're requesting this information to share with the president."
They still declined.
So I had to report that to Marcia Smith, who was the head of the Science and Technology
Division of the Library of Congress Congressional Research Service, and she asked if I would
be willing to become counsel, special counsel, to this investigation that was being conducted
by the Science and Technology Committee.
I agreed to do this, and I told her that I would need to have access to certain kinds
of information, that I would like to have declassified or get to see it.
And she said, "What would you like to see?"
And I said, "Well, the first thing I'd like to see is the classified sections of Project
Blue Book, those sections that have been referred to by Mr. Dolan earlier and by Gordon as not
really available."
Because to our surprise, I was granted permission to see them.
And they brought them to Washington, and they brought them over to the Jefferson Building,
the extension, to the Congressional Library before it was even open, the brand new building
that they built across the street.
And so I was invited to come over there.
I went over there.
No one else was in the building.
They had security people at the door, and I went over, and I was brought downstairs
into a room where they had these shoeboxes with microfilm in them and documents, et cetera.
And in my review of those documents, I came upon photographs of unquestioned UFOs.
It wasn't any question about what they were.
It wasn't a light in the sky.
It wasn't a vague report about having seen something going very fast by.
These were photographs, official United States Air Force photographs, some taken through
gun sights, but another one of a crashed saucer on the ground, that there was snow in the
photographs.
It showed that the saucer had hit into a field and had plowed across the field and was stuck
into a snowbank, set up about a 45-degree angle.
And I could see in the photographs U.S. Air Force personnel dressed in heavy parkas taking
actually film with those two cameras with the great big camera circles on top, the films
like this, so it must have been in the 1950s.
And I saw this, and I realized that I could see in one of the photographs symbols that
were on the dome of the UFO sticking in the snowbank.
So what I did, I had one of those, they were the microfiche, those little machines you
put the microfiche in, you crank the little handle, very high-tech this was.
And so what I did is they had told me that I wasn't allowed to take any notes when I
went in there.
The two security men at the door told me I was not allowed to take any notes, but I actually
had a yellow pad under my arm when I went in like this, and so when I went in and when
I saw these photographs, what I did is I cranked down the focus on the machine so that I could
get a close-up view of these symbols that were around the dome of the UFO, and what
I did is I opened up the yellow pad and I put the yellow pad in there and I traced the
actual symbols that were along the base of the saucer, and then I closed it up and I
said, "I think I'd probably better leave now because I have this."
So what I did is I put all this stuff back into the boxes and I put the yellow pad under
my arm and I walked back out, and the two security guys said, "I'd like my briefcase
back."
They handed me my briefcase and I started to walk away, and one of them says, "What's
that under your arm?"
And I said, "Oh, this is a yellow pad," and he opened it up and he leafed through all
the pages and there was nothing there, because I had put it on the inside of the cardboard.
And so I took that back with me to Jesuit headquarters and I brought it to Father Bill
Davis, who was my superior at the Jesuit headquarters, and we then agreed to go.
We gathered all 54 of the major religious denominations.
They're Washington, D.C. offices, and we brought them into a meeting and we proposed to them
from the Jesuit national headquarters that we establish as a priority having the churches
try to ascertain what information we could get, and that we would get the backing of
the churches and then go to the Vatican Library and see if we could start to address this.
Now, that is what we did, and Father Bill Davis, when I asked him this, he got puzzled
and he reached down and he pulled open the drawer out of his desk at the Jesuit headquarters
right over by DuPont Circle, 1717 Mass Ave is where we were, and he opened up the drawer
and he pulled out a photograph, and he said, "This is a photograph that I got from my sister.
Her husband is in the tower in the Seattle, Washington airport.
He's a flight controller and his best friend is a commercial pilot, and he took this photograph
out of his window of the commercial airline, and he handed me the photograph of this."
We showed this to the people at the Washington Interreligious Staff Council that we organized,
asking them if they would make this a priority, and they said, "Are there any other subjects
you'd like to discuss?"
Instead of that.
They didn't want to address that at that time, and what happened, I was contacted then by
Marsha Smith, who was directing the investigation for President Carter at the Congressional
Research Service, and she asked me if I would go to meet with the people at the Jet Propulsion
Laboratory in California in the SETI Program, the Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence,
and give them a briefing on the theological implications of contact with extraterrestrial
intelligence.
I was privileged to deliver a three-hour seminar to the top 50 scientists in the SETI Program
on the theological implications of contact with an extraterrestrial intelligence.
Then in 1994, I was contacted by Dr. John Mack, who was the chairman of the Department
of Clinical Psychiatry at Harvard Medical School, because I had graduated from Harvard
College and graduated from Harvard Law School, where I was one of the founders of the Harvard
Civil Rights Law Review, and I had gone on to Harvard Divinity School.
He contacted me and asked me if I would represent him, because he had written a book based upon
his clinical assistance to high-level military officials and others in the country who had
been sent to have psychological background done on them, who had reported these direct
contacts with extraterrestrial vehicles of this kind.
When I met with him, he had written this book, and the faculty committee at Harvard University
had called him into a session with the legal counsel from Harvard University and the head
of the dean of the medical school, getting ready to challenge his tenure for his having
written this book, that it was undermining the worldview of Harvard University.
We met with Lawrence Rockefeller, and Lawrence Rockefeller agreed to fund what would really
amount to grand rounds to present to the Harvard faculty all of the basic information that
we had on the existence of UFOs.
They then dropped the hearings and said they didn't want to have these hearings turned
into a circus.
Now those were my initial contacts with them, and so I have delivered a number of presentations
to the International UFO Congress over the years on the theological implications of contact
with an extraterrestrial civilization.
As you may know, the Vatican has now started to issue press statements.
They actually held a major press conference talking about the fact that in light of the
more recent discoveries of the increasing number of planets that they now realize have
suns and atmosphere and are in what they call the Goldilocks zone.
They're close enough to their planet, their sun and their solar systems, but not so far
away that they're likely to have potential life on them.
As these planets began to multiply, the Vatican has now held an official press conference
announcing that they in fact have now taken the position that the discovery of extraterrestrial
intelligence in a highly technologically developed intelligence is not inconsistent with Catholic
theology.
That is what is going on right now.
There are very high level meetings going on right now with the new pope to discuss what
positions are going to be taken by the International Catholic Church with regard to the theology.
My understanding is as former chief council for the Jesuits that the fact is that the
Catholic Church does not want to be behind the power curve on this issue.
They realize that with the increasing contact and discovery of these additional planets
that it's going to become clear within our generation, within our lifetimes that in fact
highly technologically developed extraterrestrial intelligence actually exists.
The findings of the Congressional Research Service that were delivered to President Carter
is that based upon all of their analysis that they have come to the conclusion, this is
an official conclusion of the Congressional Research Service, that they have come to a
95% probability projection that there are from 2 to 10 highly technologically developed
extraterrestrial civilizations within our own galaxy.
Now, remember in closing, there in our galaxy, the Milky Way galaxy, there are 50 billion
star systems in our galaxy and there are 50 billion trillion galaxies that are now known.
The question and the abiding question and it's the one that you and I discussed last
night, Congressman Bartlett, have these vehicles developed the capacity to transport vehicles
beyond the speed of light?
Because if they have, then all these questions now become focused, that that means that they
would be able to be here, come here and go and if they have, then all of these sightings
that we've talked about, all these hundreds of witnesses that we've talked about, then
are talking about a very real phenomenon.
I'll close with this one observation, when I was legal counsel for the Iran-Contra investigations,
that we were the ones that actually initially discovered the Iran-Contra weapons supply
trafficking, and when I delivered this information to Peter Rodino, who was at the time the chair
of the Judiciary Committee of the House, through Scott Armstrong, Scott Armstrong, as you'll
recall, was the staff person on Rodino's staff of the Judiciary Committee during the Watergate
investigations, who discovered the taping system in the White House that Alexander Butterfield
revealed this to Scott.
So I went and brought this information to him, and because of his close relationship
with Peter Rodino, he delivered all of the information we had about the off-the-shelf
enterprise, the involvement of Poindexter and everyone else, and the response of Peter
Rodino was, he said, "Scott," he said, "my God," he said, "if what you're telling me is
true about this off-the-shelf enterprise going on, delivering these weapons contrary to the
orders of Congress, why then," he said, "I've been telling my constituencies that they didn't
like the way that American policy was going, that they should write a letter to their congressperson,
and if their congressperson didn't do what they wanted them to do, you should vote for
someone else for Congress, but if what you're telling me is true, Scott, my God, we haven't
even been in control.
I'm not going to allow the Congress of the United States to investigate anything like
that." And that's the issue that's before us now, because if, in fact, we're not in
ultimate control, and there is an extraterrestrial intelligence of this type of sophistication
that's been visiting our planet and entering our airspace and outmaneuvering our aircraft,
it's perfectly clear that from a political consciousness that abides inside our executive
branch and inside our legislature, that is not something that they want to share with
the American people, because it would ultimately undermine the confidence of the governed in
their governors.
[applause]
My name is Lieutenant Colonel Richard French. I am one of the writers of the original Air
Force Blue Book. I was a student at Oregon State starting in 1947, and in my junior year
I was asked what specialty I wanted to be assigned when I graduated. An advisor told
me about the Office of Special Investigations. It sounded like an exciting and glamorous job,
so I volunteered. Brigadier General Carroll, a former FBI director of the Washington District,
was commissioned as an Air Force general and assumed command of the OSI.
The OSI of course was also given the added responsibility of investigating the phenomenon
of unidentified flying objects. The OSI assignment required that I have final top secret clearance
granted before I could even report for duty. That caused a delay in my reporting because
I in fact am adopted and all of my medical and birth records and all that are sealed.
Every year they straighten out that mess, and I reported to DO-20 at McCord Air Force
Base Washington. There my training officer was a special agent named John Drahos. Under
his supervision I began investigating UFO reports and recording the incidents in the
Air Force's Blue Book.
The most controversial UFO incident that occurred in my early training deserves special mention
because of its unique factor. An F-100D pilot, the Ds, they'd launch them normally just
in twos rather than fours like tactical fighters. Anyway, he pulled up on this UFO and it was
approximately 30 yards directly behind the thing. The F-86 today carries a total of 36
two and a half inch, or two and a half, let me get this straight, carries 36 of those
two and a half inch rockets and they're carried in a pod that drops and it drops and automatically
fires when it comes down. Well, he got the clearance to fire which kind of surprised
everybody and he blew that UFO out of the sky, but the problem is that the recording
of the incident, well, let me get this exactly right, the UFO intercept violated the prohibited
zone at Hanford's Atomic Energy Facility. He was a wingman and pulled up straight ahead
and it was given a clearance to fire. When the weapon fired, the pod dropped, but his
airplane exploded. They drugged the Colorado River, I mean the Columbia River in a 60 mile
area and they never found a piece or part or anything even pertaining to it. I mentioned
that I had just a very fast look at the magic report. I hope you people are familiar with
it, but if you're not, it is the original report that was prepared. President Truman
was the chairman. The people who were on that committee and I just did just get a very quick
look at it, but I could easily remember who they were because of who they were. They included
the chiefs of the president of course and also the chiefs of staff of all of the armed
forces, arms of the United States. In other words, the chief of naval operations and the
head of the Coast Guard and on and on. That terminates my presentation.
We have about 10 minutes for each member of the six of you and that will take us to 1250.
I've been asked by both the chair and the co-chair to give time reminders as we're approaching
that 10 minute limit for each of you, so I'll do that as gently as possible.
My understanding is that there will be time cue cards visible to the panelists here and
to the members back here. We will watch those and time ourselves. I remember a number of
years ago I was traveling in a car and had my car radio on and there were two news accounts.
One was that there were some UFO sightings over New Mexico and the other was that there
had been two mysterious deaths in New York City that might have been cyticosis and if
it was cyticosis it might have come from dried pigeon manure, so it was a serious suggestion
that maybe we ought to kill all the pigeons in New York. I listened to those two newscasts
and I thought, gee, if these flying saucers are extraterrestrial I think I'd wander around
a bit up there and watch for a while yet before I landed. As I said when we started this it
is really enormously arrogant and presumptive to believe that we're the most advanced civilization
in the universe. We still fight stupid wars and kill each other. There just has to be
a better way, doesn't there. Again, I will reserve my question until the end. My co-chair.
I wanted to mention one other thing. All of the time, and there's a period there that's
about 12 years, but during that 12-year period my primary job as a member of the OSI was
to debunk them. In other words, I'd come up with any kind of explanation. We'd say it
was swamp gas or you name it, anything that we could come up with to apparently convince
the general public and maintain the secrecy level on that. Some of my answers, I swear,
were observed. The swamp gas, for instance, at that time there was an average of about
three a week UFOs had descended into the Gulf Breeze, Florida area, if you know where that
is. It's just where the panhandle is in Florida. Anyway, I went down there and we observed
them just regularly, just sit there every evening with a cocktail and in they'd come.
But what was it? It was swamp gas. That was my lie and I made good on it. But that was
my actual job, to be the most artful lawyer on earth.
So Colonel French, you did a good job of it, obviously.
So for all four of you, it's just starting to weigh on me. If transparency would reveal
that we really aren't in control, that there are actually as intelligent or more powerful
than likely, more intelligent life form than humans, and that in so knowing and admitting
would be dangerous, that's a closed circle, folks. So what do you recommend? How do you
recommend we handle this? Let's start with the Colonel who won't tell us it's a gas
form.
Well, I see no other way to attack it than to come up with some kind of international
organization, something along the line of what we already have in here, or some similar
governmental way, and then putting those people, you know, because when you think about it,
this confronts religion directly and very firmly. And we do need some type of organization,
something that can hold us, if need be, to contact these people from another universe.
And when they come, you know, it's a lot better if you say, "Hi, buddy," not try and shoot
their tail end off.
So, we're claiming my time to go on to you, Daniel. But let me add a piece to this now.
Then how will the United States, for one, give up our rights as our national security
rights if we went on to cooperate with the United Nations on this?
Yes. This is a worldview issue. One of the things that I discovered after a number of
years in practice, the reason I ended up going back to Harvard Divinity School to study after
spending a number of years out practicing law, was that this is a worldview issue, that
people don't think about this very often, but the reality is there's a spectrum of
world views that are shared by our human family, the political manifestation of which, or the
political philosophy of which, is you have people who are authoritarians, you have people
who are reactionaries, you have people who are conservatives, you have people who are
moderates, you have people who are liberals, you have people who are progressives, and
then you have people who are basically what we refer to as utopianists, who tend to be
theological, for the most part. But there's a whole eighth worldview. There's an octave
of worldviews, and there's a new worldview that is in the offing right now, and that
is the worldview that is going to have to be addressed by our human family once we come
to acknowledge that there are, in fact, there's a super sophisticated, highly intelligent
extraterrestrial civilization, and that there may be more than one of these species.
Okay, I'm going to reclaim my time because I wanted to know how to break through this.
It's a new worldview. We have to construct the new worldview.
You're suggesting that we're going to take on a new worldview. If that's what it takes
to happen, we're a long way from that. Mr. Juneyos.
Well, every so often, things happen in the history of the world that change, that lead
to a complete change, and that was the case when America was discovered, and it was called
the New World, even though it was part of the same world. But at that time, it completely
changed the paradigm of the late medieval period, and there was even discussions whether
maybe the Earth paradise was in America, or whether the natives Americans had it sold.
It was a whole kind of huge discussion, and eventually, obviously, we're here, so it worked
out. Same thing when the atomic bomb was released, dropped in Japan. That changed the paradigm
of that period. I think this is the next frontier, and I don't think it's going to be as difficult
as it seems because we're conditioned already by the media and by the entertainment industry.
Even when I started this business, such as we could call it a business, this beauty,
many years ago, the attitude of people was very negative. Really, UFOs were considered
like a cookie subject, and now, if you ask a young generation, for them, they say, "Well,
what's the big deal?" It's obvious that there's life in the universe. I don't know exactly
how it will happen, but it will, and we will have to adjust and move forward.
I guess it's a good thing we have the entertainment industry to turn on people's imaginations.
Richard?
Yes. Thank you for this question. It's very important. I often think no parent is ever
ready for their first child, but they happen anyway. Disclosure of this reality, we may
or may not be ready for it. We probably won't be ready for it, frankly. I think that our
society is going through such a tremendous revolution. This isn't 1990. It's certainly
not 1950. We have capabilities today that I think are forcing this issue out. WikiLeaks
didn't exist 10 years ago because it couldn't exist. It wasn't a global infrastructure.
Cell phone cameras, all of this, this is all new. I think something's going to happen that's
going to force this out front and center. My suspicion, I can only guess, is that those
people who have knowledge on this, and I think there are such people, must be aware. They
must be aware that they cannot keep this secret forever. I think the wisest thing to do would
be judiciously and responsibly to begin allowing some of this information out. Maybe there
are controlled leaks today. I do think that when this matter is out on the table, that
doesn't mean all the answers will be there. It just means that we'll be able, publicly,
without all the joking and ridicule, to be able to talk about it as a public policy issue.
I also think that this will necessitate a geopolitical revolution. You mentioned the
issues of U.S. national security. Well, there's other countries in the world, and they're
all going to be affected by this. It will have to be necessary for there to be a true
United Nations, something that actually works that people can believe in, because without
that I think it's just going to be a big mess. Do I have any more time? Two minutes. The
next discussion, I would like to go from, we're worried about airspace. How about cyberspace?
May I make the comment at this? Basically, my background is I have more combat than virtually
anyone you'll ever meet. I have more than 800 combat missions, 860 in jet fighters,
so I'm not afraid of battle. Obviously not. I think the dumbest thing we could possibly
do is weaponize space, and I've been in that argument several times, and it would be absurd
to do that. Thank you. Thank you. Cyberspace. One minute. It's all we have. It's quite clear
that the technology that seems to be at the disposal of this civilization is able to access,
if the FBI can tap into your internet, then clearly they can too. So they're monitoring,
undoubtedly monitoring all the communications that are going on, and I would dare say that
there is a process going on of feathering into our culture, information, technology,
et cetera, that is going to soften this blow, that there's a process going on of released
information, of contact information, et cetera, and I find it based on 40 years of doing these
kind of investigations of Watergate, Iran-Contra, and others that I've been directly involved
in, that there's clearly going to be a decision made by very high level people above all of
our pay grades here, I say with all due respect from Congress people, that there'll be a decision
made to start feathering information into the culture to prepare our people for this
rather gradually, which has been going on now for the last 60 years. I think we're finished.
Thank you.
Congresswoman Kilpatrick.
Thank you very much. I think I want to start with the Colonel. I served on the Air Force
Academy Board for about six years in my 12-year tenure, 14 years in Congress. Served on the
Appropriations Defense Committee, first African-American woman ever to serve there. It's only been
three in the history of our 2,000-year country. It's outrageous. We really believe that women
have something to offer. So I really appreciate your service. We come from a "let's work this
out" kind of thing, so we wouldn't have this problem when we control the world. But having
said that, Colonel, I really appreciate your service, your time, your dedication. 800-plus.
I've been all over the world with the Defense Department, and it's been quite an experience
for me. It's really capitalized and captured my tenure in Congress, really. Why is it that
when you were there, you couldn't talk about it? Everything I've read and seen, everybody
hush-hushed it.
Wait, let me do it. I want you to do the whole question. The whole question. I know a lot
of it's from the presidential right on down to the Joint Chiefs of Staff. One of you all
spoke to that. We didn't call it by that name, but that's kind of what it was that Truman
had, exactly, as a matter of fact. Why is it now that you're at the table discussing
it with us, acknowledging that it is?
Probably it's because I'm in my 80s now.
Praise God. Okay.
Here's the problem. If you had a government job, you had to have, you need to be what
they call humanly reliable. In other words, if they thought you were a maniac or something,
you'd lose your wings, and lose your job, and so forth. Anyway, I think it's because
of that, basically the human reliability problem, the fact that there are some real lunatics
in various places, and you can't identify them well enough. Then they won't submit,
and you have a problem next to kin. If they have a child that is ill mentally, what do
you do?
You believe today that, as you sit here with us and former members of Congress, 80 plus
years of experience, having now before this committee, whose time has come, since 1968,
there's been no hearing, as you know. We're moving to that. I don't know that the answer
is another hearing right now. I'm afraid for that.
I heard in this discussion this morning, there's a lot of private things going on. I like to
see partnerships, private, public. I think that's when Americans get our best bet, when
we come together as a nation in a private, public kind of atmosphere. When you talk about
what you just said, and I agree that it's urgent, I think somebody at the table mentioned
coming together and acknowledging it, which we haven't done as this country. Other countries
are beginning to do that, and some were mentioned this morning. Do you think the Air Force will
ever come to that point? Is it a domestic, international partnership that we need? How
would you begin it? You come with the credibility.
It's necessary, and I don't think we've got much choice. Something's got to be done.
You all have to help us formulate that, too. I agree with that. Thank you very much for
your service. Mr. Sheehan, you talked about which is worse. That's how you ended that
dynamic presentation that you had. Which is worse? Do we try to put this together and
save ourselves with the world, or do we continue to put our heads in the sand that it doesn't
exist and you know that it does? I'm at a loss. You all are giving us good information,
and I think those in the audience want us to come up with some kind of recommendation,
and I can't have it both ways. You've got to be solid.
It's a very difficult issue. Because of the job assignments, when a person is a congressional
representative, for example, and has the duty of representing her or his congressional district
in the interests that are there, it's a job. As you know, a significant number of the Congress
people are lawyers. They view themselves as representing a certain client base. The problem
is that if we represent a nation state, and we insist upon maintaining the special privilege
of our citizens, the special access we have to resources in the world, etc., even to the
detriment of other nation states, we're still at a level of consciousness that is very dangerous.
Stop talking too much. Break it down for me. You've got to give me two, three points. We
don't have a lot of time. I love everything you said, but don't give it to me back yet.
You've got to have something to hold onto. We're going to have to yield some of our national
sovereignty to a global body like the United Nations.
Right there. We're not doing that. We've got leadership presidents now who don't even acknowledge
that it exists, so we're not going to yield anything. It's got to be approached to that.
Maybe we do it better because we're former elected officials, public policy makers. Can't
say it like that because the wall goes up and you don't get past it. It's got to be
a better way to say that and begin to do some of what you suggest.
It'll come probably through religious communities, that the altering of consciousness with regard
to an angelic realm, an other dimension of reality. That's where most people categorize
these types of discussions.
Okay, and that's where you worked with the Jesuit Coordination Coalition. I think that's
a good start. I think you can't leave out private industry. I think you can't leave
out the universities. I mean, it's got to be a major coalition of things and institutions
in our country and around the world that would come together more than one time with experts
like yourselves and laymen like us and others who have interest in the issue because it
is a world phenomenon. If we keep acting like it doesn't exist, then we all lose. The world
loses.
That's right.
I think time is urgent and I'm very new at the issue, so I'm just learning it even as
a member of the Appropriations Armed Service Committee. We tacitly touched it, but then
it goes away. Even at the academy where we have outstanding young men and women who dedicate
their lives to this country. They have some things that they look at and then it's put
away.
It's in the Air Force Academy book.
Exactly. Exactly right.
Talking about how to address UFOs.
Exactly.
I was going to go to the Air Force Academy.
Do you feel the urgency? Do you all feel the urgency? I'm going to say your name. Thank
you very much. Is there urgency here or are we just here just talking?
Normally, people have put it away. Officially, right? Governments, but I think in a way there
is because the potential has a very good potential. Like I said in my statement, it could really
do the trick that everything else has failed. What do we do in this earth? We have tremendous
problems besides this issue. Environmental problems, hunger and so on. Somehow, we don't
seem to be able to deal with them as a world society. There's just too much fighting and
ideological differences and religious differences. The issue of religious is very important.
Look at all the recent problems we've had internationally with certain factions of the
Islamic religion and all that. In fact, I wrote an article in the magazine about UFOs
in Islam, which was quite interesting for me to research that. Like all religions, again,
you have many factions within a religion. I do agree with Daniel. Probably if the pope
and other religious figures, they might be the way to do it. That may do the trick rather
than the political will because you know how politics are. You know better than we do how
things get very difficult. I see half a minute left. Thank you very much
for that. Just in kind of summing, trying to understand it, as an appropriator, 12 years
on the Federal Appropriations Committee with a budget of nearly $3 trillion. Biggest being
the Armed Services of $700 billion. Now we're on our knees. We don't have the money for
this or that. Could this possibly be something that can save our budget, get more resources,
make it universal, offer some kind of -- I'm looking at it from an appropriations point.
There's got to be some coming together. We spent a lot of money doing a lot of things
and never happened. Quick answer, yes.
I sit here as an appropriator looking for dollars to help save America first and incidentally
help the rest of the world. Sorry to interrupt there.
Anything that can allow an object to loiter indefinitely, instantly accelerate and do
it all silently, is using something better than petroleum for moving around.
So there must be -- whatever that answer is, there must be something implicit in the reality
of this phenomenon that will actually be a game changer. And that's really the one hope.
We've got everything so messed up and every other way looking at the world. We're not
cooperating. We're fighting. But if this is real, if there is an energy paradigm solution
here in UFO phenomenon, that by itself is worth every single effort that we can make
to get that out in the open. Thank you. Thank you very much. Senator Gravel.
Let me point out that it's not only the problem of the Congress. It's the problem of the
American people, which has been propagandized by the Congress and its leadership, that we
are superior as Americans to anybody else in the world. That's the problem. If we're
going to have a global community, we must put our humanness first before our nationality.
And what the testimony that I read is that you're talking about a paradigm change in
global governance. Now, let me ask this as a favor to you, to us, for this immediate
hearing. Would you, Antonio, get together with Daniel and the others and draft a resolution
that we could decide upon at the end of the hearings on Friday to recommend the creation
of a United Nations agency using the Granada precedent and already the numbers, the resolutions
that have been... So you draft that. It doesn't have to be 20 pages. It can be one page, maybe
two paragraphs. You draft this so that we can get our hands around something in this
regard. And then we'll have to make a decision, are we prepared as former public officials,
as private citizens, to put our money where our mouth is, and that is to be globalists
before we become nationalists. And that's the answer. So if you could provide us with
that document, do we be deeply in your debt on this side of the table?
I could start that a little bit because there's a provision in the United Nations which is
called Uniting for Peace Resolution. And Henry Kissinger told us about this in Gov 180 at
Harvard College. And he said, "If the world population ever finds out about this, we're
all in trouble," he said. I was kind of wondering who he meant by "we."
And he's right.
Yeah, that's right.
The government, the leadership is going to be in trouble once the people wake up.
That's right.
But you need a device. And right now, the device is the knowledge that you're bringing
forward, that we're trying to observe here. So first, would you bring that resolution
as soon as you can?
Sure.
We'll circulate it among the members and the leadership of the paradigm research group
--
Yeah, we can do that.
-- to seek their ecstatic.
We'll be glad to.
Now, the question I would ask, Mr. Dolan, you mentioned that the compendium of documents
that you're aware of has come about through Freedom of Information Act, has come about
by accident in many regards. Is there anything out there that document-wise backs up the
Roswell incident, that is, the crash and the humanoids? Is there any document that we could
put our hands on?
Yes, sir. There are a few very interesting documents, even as early as July 1947, FBI,
which was involved in investigating the so-called flying saucers very actively, had a memo indicating
that the debris or whatever was recovered at Roswell was being transferred to Wright
Field Dayton, Ohio, U.S. Air Force headquarters. I think that's rather interesting. Whatever
this was, if it was some kind of balloon apparatus, I think we could ask why would that be transferred
to Wright Field.
So that's interesting. There are a number of other documents that talk about rumors
within the military discussions of --
Yeah, that's not good enough to --
Right. No, no.
-- because it's hearsay.
But regarding Roswell, there was -- back in 1994, the General Accounting Office of Congress
was tasked with looking into the Roswell incident. All right. And this was on the initiative
of the late Representative Stephen Schiff of New Mexico, whose constituents asked him
to do this, and he did. Schiff talked about this at length, about how the Air Force and
the Pentagon just stonewalled him, gave him nothing, gave him a lot of expletives as well
in the process. But what the GAO's investigation was that the relevant records at Roswell from
the end of 1946 into, I think, 1948, 49 were gone. All of the records that they were looking
for, that they expected to find, were, surprise, not there. And there was no explanation given.
These were records, according to the GAO, that should not have been ever removed. They
were permanent, but they were gone. And the Air Force, by the way, was very, very deft
in their handling of this, because while the GAO investigation was going on, the United
States Air Force took the initiative and did their own study, quote-unquote "study," in
which they beat the GAO to the punch in terms of publicity, got their own thing out there
and said, oh, yeah, it was a classified balloon project known as Mogul, which was designed
to test to see whether the Soviets were detonating their own atomic devices. It's a big, big
fat report. It looks very impressive. When you actually read it, it's a load of fluff,
in my opinion. But that was their explanation. They beat the GAO to the punch and so they
won the PR war.
Thank you. Mr. Sheehan, would you address, briefly, what is the theological implication?
Yeah. Coming to grips with the full import of the theological reality is what undergirds
all of this, is that for each of us to recognize that we are incarnated in a material form,
but that there are other vibrational frequencies at which there are other dimensions of reality
going on at the same time, our theology is the realm in which we deal with it. It's a
category of knowledge in the human family in which we deal with other dimensions of
reality. What happens after death? How did we get here? What are we doing here? What's
our ultimate purpose? These are things that are raised by the UFO issue and that's why
I reiterate that it's theology, it's in the realm of theology that we have to come to
address this. When we do, what we're going to discover is that we're going to draw down
into our culture a lot of those same realities that, for example, the Native American culture
and some of the aboriginal cultures understand that they are in a dynamic relationship with
other dimensions, other vibrational frequencies. Our culture has closed itself off from that
from the time of the enlightenment in trying to define ourselves as separated, individuated
intellectual beings and that we're not in a harmonious, imbalanced relationship with
the rest of reality. The consequences, of course, are falling upon us now because of
the global climate change that we're experiencing, the contamination of our environment by ourselves.
This is the crisis. I think one of the crises that's going to confront us and that my sense
is that we're going to become much more, if we probe into the theology of all of this,
we're going to come to have a much more profound appreciation for the Native American culture
and the theology of the Native American culture and the faculty of intuitional perception
that our human family has, which is a faculty that's evolving teleologically in our culture.
This is what Teilhard de Chardin has dealt with it within the Jesuits. It's the cutting
edge of modern theology and the insights that we've gained now through quantum physics
since 1923 to 1926. We have to integrate into our scientific worldview the insights of quantum
physics and we have to begin to readjust our basic worldview, as I pointed out before,
to evolve a new worldview that integrates these capabilities.
Thank you very much. I yield back the balance of my time.
Congressman Cook.
I would like to start by asking Colonel French, you were involved in the initiations of the
Blue Book processes. Could you elaborate a little more on what you found out from that
and especially, so I have a better understanding of how that got stopped or discarded or what
exactly happened on the Blue Book and how long did that go on? I just need a better
understanding.
I'd like to start with a curve if you don't mind too much, but they ask about what happened
to the results of the accident at Alamogordo. All of that was taken to what is called the
Foreign Technology Division at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base. What was shipped, there was
physical debris, actually parts of some kind of airplane. Another unusual aspect of it
was though the metal wasn't any thicker than cellophane, but you put it in your hand and
you crush it together and it flops right back into shape. Had it analyzed, it didn't come
from Earth. There's no known, we have no known source of whatever that metal was.
You had that in your hands?
Yes.
You've actually held some of that?
So has Marcel. Jesse Marcel did the same thing.
I understand from the Roswell basically what's generally called the Roswell incident. I realize
there were several different locations of materials gathered up. There were dozens
and dozens of witnesses on the materials and you're clearly one of them. At least in terms
of the analysis of the materials, not necessarily gathering them up. Tell us about were there
witnesses of any, has been referred to as humanoid, because you don't hear nearly as
much about that.
They also were taken to the foreign technology division. There were, if I remember, about
eight or nine corpses.
I'm more interested right now in the witnesses to that. I've read the accounts, but there
were many witnesses of material.
I can't point you to anyone that can add to that except Marcel, because he was the first
one to pick it up. Went out to the crash, policed up the pieces of the airplane and
there were specific markings on them, like they were identification numbers for parts
or something of that nature. But it looked rather like Arabic writing. It didn't look
like anything from our neck of the woods.
Did Marcel indicate that he had actually witnessed the humanoid part? I know he witnessed the
answer over here. Well, and please, if anybody can illuminate.
First of all, there are quite many, many witnesses, of course, who've gone on the record about
Roswell. Unfortunately, we'll have a Roswell panel here during the meeting, and there are
a number of researchers who have specialized in that.
My question started off as the blue book.
Blue book was the US Air Force official public investigative body of UFOs from 1940. Actually,
he was a successor of a couple of previous ones, started in 1952, went up to 1969 when
it was closed down.
Okay, but it did include some of the Roswell stuff. It included nothing in Roswell, the
blue book.
No, there's nothing on Roswell.
Okay, so that was, okay, well, I just, I asked about the blue book, and what did you say
it was closed down, and what was the reason for that?
The end of 1969. Well, what happened in the 1960s is that the United States had a big,
big wave of UFO sightings, 1965, '66, made the news. Gerald Ford, congressman in Michigan,
talked about it on the floor of Congress. His constituents had seen UFOs, and he was
not satisfied with the answers that were coming from the Air Force, and the pressure was really
on the United States Air Force to do something about this. It's hard to remember because
it's so far back in time, but the Air Force was losing a lot of credibility on this. A
lot of people were not believing the Air Force explanations, and swamp gas became a big national
joke at that time, and so really all the Air Force wanted to do was just get rid of UFOs,
and so what they ended up doing was they contracted with the University of Colorado to conduct
what was to be the first true public scientific investigation of UFOs, and the whole attitude
was whatever Colorado comes up with, that's what we're going to conclude, and what that
study did, that was a whole big mess, and half the scientists got fired midway through
the project because they were believers. The man running it, Edward Condon, was absolutely
dead set against any kind of pro-UFO, pro-ET. So based on that recommendation, the Air Force
was able to wash their hands, say thank you very much, and they said we're out of the
business, we're not doing this anymore.
And there's no way to retrieve any of the, I just got to make sure I understand this,
and I appreciate it, because you've illuminated this greatly for me, but is there any way
to find out exactly what was in the Blue Book at this point then? I'm looking for--
Yes, yes.
Well, the Blue Book files are--
They're still there.
You're saying they're absolutely being covered up?
No, no, the Blue Book files are--
Oh, we can still read those. Okay, well I was confused on that issue.
The problem is--
Classified sections.
Yeah, and the problem is the Roswell stuff is not in the Blue Book files.
Okay, now I've got a better understanding of all that.
And in the prior panel, Stanton Friedman referred to a memo by General Carole Ballander in which
he stated, in closing Blue Book down in 1969, that UFO reports affecting national security
were not part of the Blue Book system, so Blue Book--
I do remember him saying that.
If I could turn to Mr. Hunaus and to Mr. Sheehan, religion has been brought up and implied in
terms of this whole thing several ways, and now you're not trying to say that just because
Pat Robertson has a particular view or because popes in the past have said things that clearly
don't agree with what you're saying as a Jesuit, that religion is somehow against the idea
of extraterrestrial life?
No, in fact, it's quite the contrary, that, remember, religion, religiro, the Latin derivative
of religiro is to relink.
The whole idea of relinking the intellect, intellectus, the root of intellect is intellectus,
the ability to distinguish the difference between.
The whole ability that we develop somewhere between osteopithecus and homo erectus, this
intellectual capacity, we alienated ourselves in a separate entity here behind our eyeballs
from all the rest of reality.
Sure.
That's the danger.
OK.
But I'm going to adjust this a little bit.
Was there an implication that it's more of the-- well, let me just say this.
Going to Christian religions in specific, you think there's some bias against the belief
in extraterrestrial?
Because you were talking about maybe we're going to have to accept this from a different
religious perspective or something.
I think that within one of the features, the unique features of Catholic Christiology,
for example, is each of the world views that I'd pointed out that have political implications,
there are subsets of Catholic and Christian theology in all of those.
So there's a reactionary world view that is fundamentalist, that everything is divided
into good guys and bad guys, and there's Satan in angelic realms, and they've projected
this satanic reality that they have onto extraterrestrials, which is very, very dangerous.
Well, I'm not in any way here to do missionary work for my particular religious faith or
certainly to speak for my religious faith.
I'm a Mormon, but on a fundamental level, many Mormons believe it's consistent with
the doctors of the church that there is life outside the church.
It's an official doctrine of the Church of the Latter-day Saints, the actual belief in
extraterrestrial intelligence.
Well, and I wanted to make that point clear.
Again, I'm not here for that to preach or anything like that, but I'm also ... I think,
and I think most Mormons believe as I do on that, would still say that's still a leap
to say that we've had the visitation, and there's nothing in the religious sense that
would prohibit that, but we need as strong an evidence as we can to help this panel open
up some congressional hearings, and by the way, I'm not giving up on the United States
Congress yet.
I don't think we have to go to the United Nations.
Maybe that might be a way, but let's also try to open this up at the United States Congress
level.
I agree.
The Catholic position on all this.
My grandmother's a Catholic.
That's all I have to do with the Catholic Church.
However, it's very important, one thing that the Catholic Church has done, and believe
it or not, they commissioned the building of a wide-angle lens to search the skies for
inbound UFOs.
It's in Tucson, Arizona, believe it or not.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much, Congresswoman Hooley.
What kind of, I mean, the reaction over the last 30, 40 years in the United States, what's
the reaction, and what has happened in the rest of the world?
What's going on?
Have there been sightings?
Do they feel differently about it than we, you know, a lot of people feel about it here?
What's happening elsewhere?
Well, as I said in my statement, the one thing that I think even skeptics would have to agree
is that the UFO phenomenon is worldwide.
It doesn't matter.
I mean, it doesn't matter the religion.
It doesn't matter the ethnic origin, the language, the culture.
It has been reported all over the world.
Now, there are some sociological differences, as you would expect, from different cultures.
But we see there's quite a rich history of UFO, even UFO investigations, official investigations,
and we will be discussing this in a few more sessions during this week about investigations.
And we have, in fact, with us some members from some of the South American agencies.
So we've seen an opening in recent years, particularly in some European countries and
particularly in South America.
Now, odd as it may seem, it almost seems to be good politics now in South America to have
a UFO investigation.
I know it sounds awkward, but the Latin culture is obviously more open.
It's much less ridicule in the media and all that about this phenomenon.
And so we've seen a trend.
It started with Uruguay back in the late '70s, and we have a representative that will be
speaking later this week.
And then Chile, Peru, Ecuador, Brazil, Argentina recently announced the creation of a UFO agency
within the Air Force.
What is interesting about the South American approach to this phenomenon from an official
point of view is that there is not an adversarial relationship between the official military
agencies and the civilian UFO committees or UFO groups.
Totally different from the United States, where even in the days of Blue Book, there
was always a big fight between ufologists, civilian ufologists, and the Air Force.
That was classic, if you read the history of UFOs in the United States.
And it used to be a little bit like that, too, in South America, not as bad as here.
But now you see that they cooperate, and usually what happens is because a lot of these agencies,
they have a limited budget, a small budget.
So they call for volunteers from the civilian community, and that shows us a model.
We don't have to have an adversarial.
We don't have to fight the government.
This is a mystery.
We should all work together in order to solve this mystery.
So that's at least some of what is going on.
But even Russia has had a lot of official investigations.
Even under the Soviet Union, there were committees from the -- there were actually two committees
that were going on in the late '70s and '80s.
One was a public one through the Soviet Academy of Sciences, and the other one was a secret
one by the KGB and the Ministry of Defense, the Soviet military.
Nobody knew about that one publicly, but the scientific one was even officially revealed
even in the controlled Soviet media.
And then, of course, under Gorbachev in the 1980s, Glasnost, it opened up, and the UFO
phenomenon became very, very popular in the late Soviet society and into modern Russia.
So China has had kind of a semi-official organization called the China UFO Research Organization.
We have one of its founding members here also attending this hearing.
So yes, you see it all over the world, and other countries actually have a more open
attitude, I mean, officially.
So it provides a model also for the U.S., in my opinion.
For any of the panelists, the other question I have, one of the other questions I have
is a lot of people, when they talk about this, at least in this country, are ridiculed when
they talk about it.
This is, you know, pooha, you know, you're somewhere in outer space.
What -- why, I guess?
Has there been some organization or is it just our attitudes in the United States tell
me why there's so much skepticism in this country?
>> I'll try to feel that.
I do find privately people are much more open about this than they are when they're in a
public situation.
That's one thing.
>> Right.
>> People discover that -- probably any of these researchers, and they discover, oh,
you research UFOs, inevitably they will say, oh, let me tell you about what I saw last
year, five years, 20 years ago.
So those stories are out there, and people -- I firmly believe there is a true hunger
for knowledge on this once people realize that there's something to it.
But I agree with you, in our public discourse, this is a third rail, whether you are in major
media or politics or academia, they're all really the same in this regard.
I had a professor at UCLA call me a number of years ago, a department chair said, well,
I really just want to let you know I enjoy your books.
I said, thank you.
Why are you whispering in the phone?
Which literally he was whispering, and he said the typical thing that every professor
would say, well, my department is kind of political and not go -- right.
So it's always the retired ones who look for me.
But personally, I believe, you know, the tone was set back in the '50s.
And in fact, the top skeptic debunker in the U.S. at that time was a Harvard astronomer
by the name of Donald Menzel.
Menzel wrote a number of books.
He was like the pit bull guard dog maintaining orthodoxy.
You know, if some little community college professor was going to get out of line and
talk about UFOs, here's Menzel, Harvard astronomer, who's going to argue with Menzel?
And he'd slap them down.
Menzel, we learned years later, had a very, very close relationship with the National
Security Agency, very close.
Does this prove that the NSA used him in this capacity?
Who knows?
But these things -- this is how it looks.
Back in the late 1970s, journalist Carl Bernstein had the famous Rolling Stone article in which
he said there are over 400 U.S. journalists that I have identified who had a covert relationship
with the Central Intelligence Agency.
CIA promptly said, "Well, we don't do that anymore."
And if you read the language carefully in their statements, especially in the 1990s,
they're very lawyerly in their denials, it's very clear that there are relationships.
So what I am suggesting, and I guess this is the conspiracy angle here, but I would
suggest that there are proxies that work with national security elements.
Look, it's an open revolving door in much of our society anyway.
Most of this is out in the open, but I think that there are relationships, friendly relationships
with academic and with media and political as well, where you have the herders who basically
keep the underlings in line.
And every now and then someone gets out of line and they have to be dealt with.
So I think that that's where the culture is created and it has a top-down effect.
And most people, they don't want to be Superman.
They have their jobs, they have got their family, they got their things, they can't
fight the machine.
So they just, they live their lives and hope that someone else takes it on.
And there are documents that Mr. Dolan can tell you about, the internal documents in
the Air Force and others where they consciously instruct their officers to ridicule and debunk
people, is a specific official policy inside the Air Force.
People they know positively have seen one of these things to try to destroy their credibility.
Yeah.
In the Robertson panel, which is a famous CIA symposium that took place in January of
1953, in fact, they used the word "debunk."
It's in the document itself.
As the Colonel says, you know, specifically assigned to go out and ridicule them and tell
them they're ridiculous.
And most people can't stand up against that kind of thing coming from authority figures.
Right.
The Robertson panel was the last act of the Truman administration, it was the last weekend
of Harry Truman's presidency that this classified panel took place, and it was specifically
related to UFOs.
Very interesting little historical factoid there.
And as Daniel just pointed out, its conclusion was, this is a necessary topic and we must
debunk it to the American people.
This is not a good thing for them to be thinking about, and they were working with the media
to do that.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Where was the balloon, the Mogul balloon that was supposed to have been the Roswell incident,
from where was it supposedly launched?
The Mogul, I thought they were at White Sands, Alamogordo, that area.
We have the record, I'm so sorry.
From where?
You know what a pie ball is, it's a high-altitude balloon that they track, they launch them
and then track them so they can keep track of upper air currents.
But when it was launched, when Marcel launched the thing, he would have been probably standing
right in front of base ops because that's where they send them up from.
From where?
Base operations.
You see the fighter squadrons or bomber squadrons or whatever they have, their own particular
area, but transient airplanes always launch from base operations.
How close is one of those to Roswell?
It's on Roswell base.
So what they're saying is that the balloon was launched there and crashed there.
Yes.
I don't know where exactly that it crashed.
See, these balloons were supposed to be determining possible Soviet nuclear detonations.
I'm just curious where they, because if it was launched somewhere else, the probability
that landing at Roswell was vanishingly small.
I had a course in advanced statistics and it's vanishingly small probability.
The United States Air Force in their 1994 reports said these were launched out of White
Sands and actually they had a schedule of a number of these balloon launches that went
down and were recovered.
So there were several that were from the spring of 1947 and in fact they speculated, this
wasn't really a slam dunk, but they indicated that they thought that they'd identified the
one launch that was in fact supposedly the Roswell crash and I'm trying to remember the
date on that.
As has been mentioned, the curious thing about all of this is in the GAO report, there was
nothing for them to look at because all of the relevant information had been destroyed.
They had no idea at whose command had been destroyed and this is very unorthodox.
It should have been there.
Kind of interesting, isn't it?
I was a member of the Science and Technology Committee, I think it was simply called the
Science Committee then.
When Schiff held this, I thought it was a hearing apparently, it was a briefing and
it was what, about '94 or '05, I came to the Congress in '93 and I remember his interest
in that.
When I was first approached about this week's activities, I was cautioned that if you do
this you could possibly be relegated to the lunatic fringe and this may not be good for
your potential activities for the rest of your political productive life.
I'm 87 in five weeks, so I don't know how much remains anyhow, but I said, "I'm going
to do this because I think there's a very serious constitutional issue involved here."
Whether there are UFOs or not, whether they are extraterrestrial or not is really quite
irrelevant to whether or not there ought to be hearings on this because the First Amendment
to the Constitution says, "The right of the people to petition the government for a redress
of grievances."
Mr. Sheehan, doesn't this fall within that?
Oh yes, there's no doubt about this, but the fact of the matter is in a national security
state, from the passage of the National Security Act of 1947, there has been an entire caveat
on the Constitution that things that fall under national security, when Oliver North
can sit right in front of you and say, "Sure, I lied to you, the Congress, because this
was a covert operation, that we're in charge, you're not in charge."
There's an entire national security state kind of subculture that believes that they
have the right, not only to hold information back from Congress, but to openly defy Congress.
When you pass the Boland Amendment, prohibiting them from engaging in the covert operations
against Nicaragua, they go ahead and do it anyhow.
The danger as a national security state, and if it arose in the context of the Cold War
with the Soviet Union, we should move very aggressively at the end of the Cold War to
try to disassemble some of those structures of the national security state, not try to
create a new one, so that they went searching very quickly for some ultimate other that
they had to find, and they ended up having Afghanistan, or Iran, or Iraq.
It's a mindset, and it's that whole kind of retrenchment into a defensive position in
the face of the ultimate other.
It's an ultimate mindset that we have to try to overcome, and as I point out, it's a theological
issue because that is a malfunction of our intellect, and it cuts us off from our harmonious
relationship not only with the rest of the universe, but all other intelligent species
in the universe, and that's what we have to address, I think.
It's a worldview issue.
Thank you.
For 20 years in the Congress, I served on the Armed Services Committee, and I remembered
Eisenhower's caution as he left office, that we should be concerned about the military-industrial
complex.
I understand that in the original draft, it was military-industrial-congressional complex,
and he didn't want to be too political, so he took out the congressional.
It's too bad he did that, because this really is a military-industrial-congressional complex.
The F-35 is built in 48 states.
There are 96 senators, and I don't know how many hundred representatives support the F-35,
not because we may need it, but because it creates jobs.
Too many of us cannot differentiate between jobs that consume wealth and jobs that create
wealth.
It's on the front page of the Washington Post today.
You look at the headlines of the Washington Post, and it says that the sequester of trying
to cut back on the military budget, all the arguments are coming out now.
We can't do that because of all the jobs and the employment.
It's an old saw.
We've developed an economy that is so reliant upon military spending that, in fact, it drives
the policies to go looking for adversaries.
If we lose the adversary of the Soviet Union on December 31st of 1991 with the dissolving
of the Soviet Union, it takes them less than a few years to find another one.
If you have to go so desperately that you're looking to Afghanistan and Iran as being your
ultimate threat to the most powerful nation in the history of the human civilization,
there's a motive for that, and it's not because they're threatening you.
We had a hearing on this in the Congress about the economic effects ... If I was chairman,
I wouldn't have held a hearing ... economic effects of sequestration.
When it came time for my question, my five minutes, I said, "Suppose when we left here
tonight we broke all the windows out of this building, and we did that all over Washington,
and overnight a crew came in and replaced all of those broken windows, and we did this
every day.
We broke out all the windows and the crew would replace them all.
Wouldn't that create a lot of jobs?
Just think of the jobs that that would create."
My question was, do you think that would have a long-term beneficial effect on the economy?
I wanted them to understand the difference between jobs that create wealth and jobs that
consume wealth.
Well, we've been talking about the Constitution and why I'm here.
I'm here because I think that the Congress owes the American people a hearing on this
subject.
You may be dead wrong.
There may be nothing to UFOs.
That is irrelevant.
You have a right to petition the government for redress or grievances.
All of my questions have been anticipated by my colleagues.
Thank you all very much for a very good panel, and we'll now stand in recess for lunch.
Thank you.