>> This hearing is in order. We've got our witnesses ready and --
>> And gentlemen, if you could stand and repeat after me.
I do hereby affirm. >> I do hereby affirm.
>> That I will tell the truth. >> I will tell the truth.
>> And nothing but the truth. >> And nothing but the truth.
>> To this committee today. >> To this committee today.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. >> And before I move to the next witness,
if I could just indicate that I'm pleased. I don't know if you have a copy of the letter.
Yes, you do. So if you could hand that to me.
>> Would you like to read this? >> Well, no. Dr. Bookman, I'd have you read
that letter. >> There's not just one letter that the committee
created. We also have all six members who have signed this because it does not deal
with a foreign government. It deals with the Veterans Affairs Administration and is also
addressed to the President of the United States. We're all six members of this committee, and
I won't take the time to read it. You're welcome to come up later. Basically demand
that Jim Pinnison and Airman Burroughs be granted their medical records from this government.
>> Just a point of personal privilege, if I can just say that beyond the obvious benefits
to those two heroic former members of the United States Air Force, the release of those
records, the obvious medical benefits are clear, and that's alone enough reason for
us to sign that. But the obvious implications of what's on those records in terms of breaking
down the wall or putting another crack in that truce embargo are, I think, obvious to
people in this room for sure. Let's go to our esteemed Honorable Paul Hellyer of Canada.
We would give you 20 minutes, sir. >> Thank you very much, Mr. Chair, and thank
you for giving me this opportunity to speak. My name, as I said, was Paul Hellyer. I'm
a former Minister of National Defence for Canada. I served in three governments during
a total of 23 and a half years as a member of Parliament. Although as Minister of National
Defence, I had sighting reports of UFOs. I was too busy to be concerned about them at
the time because I was trying to unify the Army, Navy and Air Force into a single Canadian
Defence Force, and that itself was a kind of battle to the finish. So this was not high
on my agenda. But about 10 years ago, I started getting interested due to a young man from
Ottawa sending me material on the subject. I told him I was too busy to read it, but
he had confidence that someday I would. He sent me a copy of Colonel Corso's book, The
Day After Roswell. It took me a while to get around to reading it, but I took it for my
summer reading in 2005 and was really impressed with what was contained in it. And what I
thought to myself is there are huge issues here, huge issues, and the American people
and the people of the world have a right to know what's going on because they're part
of it. It's not just an isolated thing. And so after confirming the contents of the book
with a retired United States Air Force General, I accepted the invitation of Victor Vigiani,
who's over here somewhere, and his cohort, Mike Bird, to speak to a symposium at the
University of Toronto. And I said, UFOs are as real as the airplanes flying overhead.
That gave me the dubious distinction of being the first person of cabinet rank in the G8
group of countries to say so unequivocally. Since then, I've learned a lot from many
sources, including a number of the fantastic witnesses that we have heard these last four
days. So they're so outstanding. I was just really blown away with them, the amount of
information that was available. And I appreciate every single one of them. But because I'm
not a ufologist, I'm a politician, there are only a few things that I want to add in that
particular realm. The first is that about in the 1960s sometime, there was a flotilla
of UFOs headed south that crossed into NATO territory in Europe. And the commander-in-chief
of the Supreme Allied Headquarters in Europe was naturally very shaken. Fortunately, or
maybe divine providence before the panic button was pushed, the flotilla turned around and
headed back north. Obviously, they had thought maybe they were Russian and they were very
concerned about it. Anyway, an investigation was launched into this whole subject. And
a document was prepared which concluded that at least four species had been visiting Earth
for thousands of years. And this is my own view at this stage as well. So except for
that, there are just a couple of things that we've talked about that I'd like to refer
to. And one was that we were referring to them as they until this morning when Linda
Bolton Howe, I think she was the first one, actually named three different species. I
have brought my latest book called Light at the End of the Tunnel, the Survival Plan for
the Human Species as an aide-memoire. And I named five different species here. I'm aware
of more now. As a matter of fact, I saw a document just a few days ago that mentioned
20. And I thank you, Mr. Chairman. We're interested in some of the places they might come from.
So I have in here Zeta Reticuli, the Pleiades, Orion, and Romita, and the Altair star systems.
So I don't think we can any more refer them to them as they because they're not an amorphous
mass. They are different species and consequently may have different agendas. I don't think
we can say that they all have the same agenda any more than that we could say that the United
States, China, and Russia had the same agenda. Our real interests may be very similar, but
as of now our perceived interests are still quite far apart. One more observation before
I begin what I want to say, and that is that we spent quite a bit of time talking about
the 66 year old cadavers. And I was glad to have Linda this morning finally say that there
are live ETs on earth at this present time, and at least two of them probably working
with the United States government. The seventh, the other species that I learned about not
too long ago was called the tall whites. And this is when Paula Harris broke the story
just a few years ago. And through her good offices I had the chance to talk for about
three hours with former Airman Charles Hall and listen to this absolutely fascinating
story of how he was working. First of all he was scared out of his skin, but after that
when he got to know them how he was working with and finally they became to trust each
other and have a good working relationship with the tall whites at the gunnery range
at Indian Springs in Nevada. And these tall whites were living on United States Air Force
property and working in cooperation with the United States Air Force and sharing technology
with them. He wrote a book incidentally called Millennial Hospitality. There are four different
versions but Paula says that Millennial Hospitality number two is the best. I think that's the
one I read and it's a very interesting read if you want to sort of get inside the problem
of what it's like to bump into these people floating across the terrain in the desert.
Enough on that for now, my interest is in full disclosure. And I just, my only caveat
is I think probably I would say 95 to 98 percent full disclosure. I know of one or two things
that I'm not sure should be in the public domain at least yet. They will be someday
I'm sure but not maybe immediately. But just as children survive the idea of the tooth
fairy and Santa Claus when they become adult, I think that taxpaying citizens are quite
capable of accepting the new and broader reality that we live in a cosmos teeming with life
of various sorts. The fact that some other civilizations are more advanced than we are
may be humbling but that could be a necessary step in our survival. The world is an unholy
mess. We have it best until the end of this decade. In my book I said we have ten years
to stop global warming if we don't want it to be beyond the point of no return. Two years
has gone past since it was written so I say we have until the end of the decade to arrest
global warming. Yet our leaders don't even talk about it very much except in a superficial
way. They appear to be more interested in starting wars to control more oil and in effect
prolong the gravity of the threat. Of course even if they took the problem seriously they
wouldn't have the finances to finance the transition from oil to the clean economy to
the clean energy because we have an infinitely silly banking and financial system in the
western world. And the United States Congress I regret to say is partly responsible and
I'd be glad to elaborate on that later if you're interested. And finally they need the
technology for clean energy and it exists and it's being kept secret by the same vested
interests who control our destiny. Who are these vested interests and what are they up
to? Well, Senator, we're talking about a military hunda. In my opinion that is true but I have
broadened and deepened the definition to cabal and the cabal comprises members of the three
sisters. The Council on Foreign Relations, the Bilderbergers and the Trilateral Commission,
the International Banking Cartel, the Oil Cartel, members of various intelligence organizations
and select members of the military unit who together have become a shadow government of
not only the United States but of much of the western world. The Council on Foreign
Relations is the oldest of the three sisters and as early as October 1940, years before
Germany surrendered to the allied armies to vaporize Hitler's vision of empire, the Council's
economic and financial group drafted a memorandum outlining a comprehensive policy "to set forth
the political, military, territorial and economic requirements of the United States in its political
potential leadership of the non-German world including the United Kingdom itself as well
as the western hemisphere and the far east." The Council made no effort to disguise the
fact that the purpose of the Grand Area and later world hegemony was to support an expanding
U.S. economy, to provide it with raw materials and markets for its products. This was labeled
the "national interest." It was equally clear that the national interest was the interest
of the ruling elite whose members comprised the Council. The real interests of the majority
of rank-and-file Americans was never a factor in the equation. So Mr. David Rockefeller
who is a member of all three of the sisters is quoted as saying this at a meeting of the
Bilderbergers in Europe. We are grateful to the Washington Post, the New York Times, Time
Magazine and other great publications whose directors have attended our meetings and respected
their promises of discretion for almost 40 years. It would have been impossible for us
to develop our plan for the world if we had been subjected to the lights of publicity
during those years. But the world is more sophisticated and prepared to march toward
a world government. The supranational sovereignty of an intellectual elite and world bankers
is surely preferable to the national auto-determination practiced in past centuries. He of course pretended
he didn't say that, but the witness is reported by Daniel Estulin, a thoroughly reliable reporter
who has written the true story of the Bilderberger group. And if you want to really get inside
of what's been going on there for this long time, that's a good place to go. So anyway,
you hear what Mr. Rockefeller said and so there you have it. The aim of the game is
a world government comprising members of the cabal who are elected by no one and accountable
to no one. And according to Mr. Rockefeller, the plan is well advanced. Does this help
you to understand why our civil rights are being taken away from us? I say us because
Canada too is included in the grand plan. A giant leap in the wrong direction followed
the end of the Cold War. No one could have been happier than I was when the Berlin Wall
came down on November the 9th, 1989. The elation on our side of the curtain was near universal
and very significant on the other side as one country after another regained its freedom.
Nearly everyone believed that it was the dawn of a new era of peace and prosperity for people
everywhere. There was much talk of a peace dividend. The prospects were dazzling, dazzling
in their scope and diversity. It was a unique and God-given opportunity for a new braver
and fairer world. We blew it. We blew the chance of a lifetime to do good things. A
small group of zealots undermined our golden opportunity to pursue peace, not war, and
little did we dream that they had a vastly different vision of the new world order. Their
plan, which is now commonly known as the Project for a New American Century, included preventive
wars and clear violation of international law, regime change wherever and whenever the
U.S. desires and if they can get away with it without excessive casualties, and the establishment
of a kind of economic and cultural hegemony with America acting as "constabulary." That
was their word, globally. This was to be accomplished without authority of the United Nations and
without the restraint of existing international treaties. It would involve a military buildup
unprecedented in peacetime history and could trigger an arms race which is precisely the
opposite of the peace dividend that the world had rightly looked forward to. The Machiavellian
scheme involved secret police, the curtailment of civil liberties and defiance of the U.S.
Constitution, and a moribund economy operating way below its potential, exactly those features
for which the Soviet Union was held in contempt. The initial draft of the document was so controversial
when it was leaked to the New York Times that it had to be rewritten, but it was not changed
very much, just the cosmetics, enough to make it politically acceptable. The document said
this, "May have been easy to persuade President Bush to abandon his stated policy of not getting
America more deeply involved in international affairs, but persuading the American people
would be more difficult. Sophisticated Americans would question such a giant sea change in
history. The authors of Rebuilding America's Defenses, Strategy, Forces, and Resources
for a New Century recognize this difficulty from the outset because their document contained
the following sentence. Further, I'm quoting, "Further, the process of transformation, even
if it brings revolutionary changes, is likely to be a long one, absent some catastrophic
and catalyzing event, like a new Pearl Harbor." It wasn't too long before they got their catastrophic
and catalyzing event. Terrorists struck the World Trade Center in New York and the Pentagon
in Washington on September the 11th, 2011. Incidentally, they have removed the sentence
about Pearl Harbor in the document that you can now get if you went to the internet to
find it. Almost the whole world mourned. Canada mourned. The overwhelming majority of Muslims
condemned the treacherous attacks. My sympathy for the friends and families of the injured
and dead was genuine and unwavering to this day. My sympathy for the U.S. government began
to grow a bit thin, however, when I heard President Bush cite the reasons for the attack.
And I quote, "Why do they hate us?" he asked rhetorically in an address to the Congress.
They hate what they see right here in this chamber, democratically elected government.
Their leaders are self-appointed. They hate our freedoms, our freedom of religion, our
freedom of speech, our freedom to vote and assemble and disagree with each other. I felt
sad when I heard the President's word. I assumed that he believed what he was saying. But if
that were true, he was profoundly ignorant of the real thoughts and feelings of people
in other parts of the world. If he wanted to hear the truth, he should have listened
to Osama bin Laden who was well informed concerning the origins of the kind of fanatical hatred
of the United States which has led to such treachery. This is his version of events.
Every Muslim must rise to defend his religion. The wind of faith is blowing and the wind
of change is blowing to remove evil from the peninsula of Muhammad. Peace be upon him.
As to America, I say to you and its people a few words. I swear to God that America will
not live in peace before peace reigns in Palestine and before all the army of infidels depart
the land of Muhammad. Peace be upon him. That is clear enough. The dislike of America has
nothing to do with democracy versus dictatorship or wealth or freedom of religion or freedom
of assembly. It is directly related to American foot dragging and stick handling, a just settlement
of the Palestinian question.
Mr. Heller, I hate to interrupt. Time has expired but I'm very happy if the panel has
no objection to allow another minute or two to finish your statement. How much time do
you think you need to finish it?
I think probably somewhere between one and five minutes most.
I think we'll give you two minutes to finish your statement as much as I'd like to grant
more. Thank you.
Okay. In short, American foreign policy was the root of the conflict. So here we are more
than a decade later fighting another war that can't be won. There is no country on earth
powerful enough to protect its citizens against fanatical hate as we learn from the Boston
Marathon. And the mere attempt to pursue the impossible pits neighbor against neighbor
and the state power structure against everyone. All of the freedoms won by the millions of
men and women who fought and died in World War II are being flushed unceremoniously down
the drain. The only hope of peace is a negotiated settlement. This will require a paradigm shift
in American attitudes. It involves a de facto renunciation of the plan for a new American
energy and the adoption of a pledge of cooperation with all humankind to build the kind of world
which we are collectively capable of.
Young people everywhere need to be challenged by a noble cause. They need to be involved
in arresting global warming, creating a banking system that is just and sustainable and lead
the way in the transformation to the new reality that we have to live in harmony with our celestial
neighbors as well as seeking peace on earth. In a word, we have to become spiritual beings
and practice the one tenet that the world's major religions have in common, and that is
the golden rule.
And this field too, and I just want to read one paragraph at this time if you'll allow
me, Mr. Chair. This is from the late Dr. John Mack, an American secular Jewish psychiatrist
who became a world leader in interviewing abductees or experiencers, as he called them,
came to this conclusion in a startling book, Passport to the Cosmos. Quote, "Although the
aliens are not themselves gods, their behavior is sometimes anything but godlike. Abductees
consistently report that the beings seem closer to the godhead than we are, acting as messengers,
guardian spirits or angels, intermediaries between us and the divine source." Thank
you.
Thank you very much. We'll now hear from Richard Dolan for ten minutes.
Thank you, distinguished members of the committee, and let me just say it's been an honor for
me personally to be here with you all week to be able to give statements to you and chat
with some of you privately as well.
Regarding disclosure, I have often felt that disclosure on the matter of UFOs and ETs,
possible extraterrestrials, is a paradox. It's impossible, but it is inevitable. It's
impossible because there is no political motivation for it. It's inevitable, however, because
our leaders are not the only factor in this equation. There are other beings, after all,
but mainly I would say there is us, the people, who are going through this greatest social,
cultural, and especially technological transformation in the history of humanity. In fact, I would
say that we are the game changers.
One day, and it won't be too long in the future, something is going to force someone's
hand. It could be a major sighting. It could be a major leak. Something. Something that
can no longer be denied. After all, we are fast approaching what experts in artificial
intelligence call the singularity when computing intelligence exceeds our own. In such a future,
I ask you, can we really think we will still be stuck in neutral on this issue? Something
will force the president's hand. He or she will finally hold that long-awaited press
conference and make that bombshell statement. It might go something like this.
I have been advised by the National Security Council and heads of our intelligence community
that there is a reality to some of the UFO phenomenon, in that some UFOs are real physical
craft not manufactured by any known civilization on earth. Or words to that effect.
It's the kind of statement that many proponents of UFO disclosure would like to hear, but
the real question is what next? Because there would be quite a few follow-up questions.
At the top of the list will be questions about who these other beings are and what their
agenda or agendas might be. This will be a very difficult question for any president
to answer. In the first place, there is a likelihood
that even the leaders of the black budget or breakaway society that have been on top
of this for years, they may not even know. Or at least not fully. And what if they do
know? And moreover, what if at least some of that answer includes information that might
be upsetting? Divining the intentions of non-human visitors, or permanent residents, whatever
they may be, might not be the easiest thing to do. But it's entirely possible, judging
from the data we do have, that some of them may not care very much about humanity. Some
may. Some may not. And what if an agenda has been determined within the intelligence community
and this agenda includes something to do with alleged abduction phenomenon? And even if
that isn't true, does any president honestly believe he or she can contain rampant speculation
along these lines? And even if the intentions of these other beings are said to be neutral
or positive, there will clearly be tremendous suspicion by large swaths of humanity. This
will not be an easy sell. There will already be a sizable number of people predisposed
to interpreting these other beings as nothing less than demonic, short of bringing one of
these entities to a podium and subjecting it to hours and days and weeks of questions
by an insatiable public. It's very likely that any moment of disclosure will not satisfy
the public the way it would like to be regarding alien motivations. That's only the beginning
of the problems. One early and obvious question that will arise, one which will have deep,
profound political implications, will be very simple. How long have you managed to keep
this secret all these years? Consider that our entire society has been told that UFOs
do not represent anything truly anomalous, that ETs or aliens are definitely not here
on earth interacting with us, that UFO believers may be well-meaning but had been mistaken
about all of that. This has been a mindset embedded within all of our major institutions.
Our educational institutions from primary school through universities and postdoctoral
levels throughout our major news organizations in which an open belief in UFOs is a third
rail for one's career, throughout our scientific establishment for sure and also throughout
our political structure. Political careers have been destroyed or at least severely undermined
by the UFO taint. Remember what happened to Dennis Kucinich in 2008 after it became known
that many years before he had seen a UFO. Never mind the fact that the two witnesses
he had been with came out and corroborated the sighting. They saw the same thing. All
of these institutions and others have treated the UFO topic as nothing more than a joke,
something suitable for immature minds. Can it really be that the professors throughout
the United States uniformly have dismissed this phenomenon without any cooperation from
the intelligence community? Ditto the world of science, politics and media. Well, no.
Not when the most modest amount of research shows strong intelligence community influence
over all of these institutions. In other words, people will see very clearly that the national
security apparatus has created a global culture that has suffocated the truth. Researchers
will begin to investigate in a serious way just how these relationships have undermined
the credibility of all those institutions and undermined our apprehension of truth.
The result will be a major cultural and institutional house cleaning, but it won't stop there.
Investors will naturally want to know specifics about the structure of secrecy itself. That
is, they will want to know if the U.S. president has been out of the loop all these years,
as it seems, then who exactly has been in the loop? Who has been running the UFO cover-up?
If the answer is anything along the lines of my own research so far, it will show that
the cover-up has long ago gravitated away from formal presidential authority into international
and private hands. It's not that the U.S. president is a non-player in all of this,
but rather is more like the public face of the true power elite that stands behind. We
all, I think, have come to understand this when it comes to power in general, and this
will likely be the case when we begin a sophisticated analysis of UFO secrecy. In other words, the
moment of disclosure will trigger an intellectual revolution worldwide relating to the true
structure of power on planet Earth. It will be a moment in which the world sees and acknowledges
that the emperor has been wearing nothing at all. The political fallout will be tremendous
and a great battle will develop within the first year of disclosure. Think of it this
way. Just because the president has been forced into making an announcement doesn't mean
that the CIA and all the other intelligence groups that have been managing this will simply
walk away. There has been a concerted effort spanning an entire human lifetime to control
this topic. A great deal has been invested and mere disclosure is not going to change
that. The real issue in the immediate post-disclosure world will be who controls the spin on the
story, because right away there will be a great divide, a chasm. Once this topic is
available for open discussion, you can be sure that people around the world will be
demanding answers. You can be just as sure that on the other side of the fence information
will be handed out as sparingly as possible. Government spin doctors will be out in great
numbers trying to control the situation according to national security policy, although this
time independent UFO searchers may get a public hearing that they hadn't gotten before. If
the official spokespersons are making misleading or false statements, it's going to be a bit
easier post-disclosure for independent researchers to point this out, because this time the world
will be much more likely to listen. And there will be many, many more investigators into
this topic after disclosure than there are today. How all that will turn out, only time
will tell. There are so many other messy issues relating to global finance, energy, truth
commissions, lawsuits, cultural transformations, cultural wars, religious and spiritual changes,
scientific paradigm shifts, and ultimately geopolitical changes that will allow us to
meet the challenge of, shall we call them others, here on planet Earth in some sort
of coordinated, hopefully logical manner, and even more hopefully in some way that answers
to the people rather than a handful of elite human players. And for that, we will need
a groundswell of public pressure from below and tremendous political energy, ethics, and
courage to take on the black budget culture that has dominated this subject for so long
and to begin a long, hard fight to reclaim some measure of freedom and dignity for humanity
while we begin a new, better, and more mature phase of our existence. Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Gollin. Now we'll go to our next witness, Daniel Sheehan, for 10 minutes.
Good afternoon. Again, I point out that I'm speaking in this context as our general counsel
here for this gathering and our meeting. And I do this in the context of having served
as an attorney, as I pointed out in my initial comments on the first day we gathered, that
I have for various reasons ended up being the attorney for a number of different issues
having to do with attempting to uncover ongoing cover-ups. From the time that I served as
one of the attorneys for the New York Times and the Pentagon Papers case, having seen
the 47 volumes of the concealment of a policy that was completely contrary to what was being
publicly professed and told to the Congress, in fact. And then I ended up being counsel
in the Karen Silkwood case, uncovering the fact that our central intelligence agency
was smuggling 98% pure bomb-grade plutonium to Israel, et cetera. I pointed out at the
beginning of this conversation this week. And I pointed out that I ended up in the Iran
Contra case as being the ones who, one of the ones that brought the information, attempted
to bring it to Congress. And I want to point out here just at the very top of my conversation
to repeat the reaction on the part of Peter Rodino, who was the chairman of the House Judiciary
Committee at the time, when the information concerning the off-the-shelf self-financing
covert operations enterprise that had been set up by the chief of covert operations for
the central intelligence agency, Theodore Shackley, under George H.W. Bush, that when
he was told this by Scott Armstrong, one of his trusted confidants, that Peter Rodino's
response was, "My God, my God, Scott, I've been telling people for years that if they
didn't like the way that our American policy was going, that they should write a letter
to their congressperson. But if their congressperson did not respond, they should vote for someone
else to be their congressperson. But if what you're telling me here is true, why then we
haven't even been in charge? I'm not going to allow the United States Congress to investigate
anything like that." Now, that's an absolute quote from Peter Rodino as the chairman of
the Judiciary Committee. This had only to do with the fact that there was a covert operation
going on attempting to supply military equipment to the Contras. Now, what we're dealing with
here is we've come full circle during the course of this week. We've discovered that
the three major questions that have been in front of us, that being that what in the world
is going on here with this phenomenon of so-called unidentified flying objects or the flying
saucers themselves when we move beyond the unidentified nature of them, and these beings
that seem to be associated with these vehicles that have been seen on a number of occasions.
That's one of the big major questions. The second major question is, "Well, who in the
world is it that knows what the answer to this question is?" Since so many of the government
officials don't seem to know, yourselves included, one of the extraordinary events of the week
has been watching the transition take place from six of our trusted and long-time representatives
actually coming to discover that the information that actually exists about this is extraordinary
and very detailed. It addresses the issue of the radar sightings. It addresses the issues
of all the questions that have been asked, and it comes to an observation that not only
does the Congress not know about this, but many people throughout the executive branch
don't know about this. This question of who is it that does know about this, or is there
anybody that knows about this? What we have heard over and over again in the testimony
is that there are many pieces of evidence that indicate that this is known about, that
there was an agency set up by President Truman shortly after the discovery of the crash site
at Roswell in 1947, the Majestic 12 group. There's been clear testimony that I believe
is credible, would be credible in a court of law, that this organization has for various
reasons taken this issue out from under the oversight of our Congress, out from under
the control of our executive branch, and has taken this into a realm of semi-private control.
What you'll notice is as we come to the last panel of our week together here, the issue
tends to turn more and more to that issue. What has happened to our country when a national
security state seems to have arisen to conceal certain types of information from our people,
from our congressional representatives, even from some of our presidents. That question
seems to be in front of us right now, attempting to understand the nature of this elite group.
What we want to do also is face the third question, is that when you get past these
procedural questions to the ultimate question of who are these beings, what are the implications
for our human family if we are, in fact, at a point of some rather dramatic transition.
I believe that what we're going to be experiencing in the very near future has been foreshadowed,
as I mentioned earlier, by the positions being taken by the Catholic Church and the Vatican,
that they are very clearly attempting to move into a position of utilizing the increasing
discovery of more and more planets on which they are more and more confident that life
is going to be discovered and that they're going to eventually not only recognize that
at least microscopic life has been discovered, but that a civilization has been discovered
and they're going to begin by pointing out that it's okay because they're very far away.
We've discovered them, we've found the information, but they're very far away and they're going
to engage in a process of feathering this consciousness into our people and that they're
only then going to point out that this civilization seems to be a highly developed technological
civilization and we will then reveal the existence of communication mechanisms that we have developed
whereby we can have a longer range diplomatic type of negotiation with this civilization.
They're going to say let's not turn to the past, let's not reflect upon all this information
and evidence that's been around for a long time that they seem to be here, we've known
about it, there's been concealment about this, there may be concealment of certain technology
that they've made, we had available to us, just as was said by the Obama administration,
let's not look back at George W. Bush's administration, let's not review the question of the torture
and the lying to the Congress of the United States to get us involved in this, let's not
do that, let's look forward and be constructive, that's how we're all trained and what I'm
saying is that I think we've come to try to share some of that consciousness here this
week, what can we do to look forward to this and that's why the resolution has been put
forth here to try to reach out and have a set of conferences sponsored by the United
Nations General Assembly start to reveal this information so we can participate in this
to avoid a dialectical confrontation between the people of our country and this national
security state apparatus, some of the details of which have been pointed out here in our
final panel and I share in that wish to have this done constructively and peacefully and
I believe that we can do that and I believe that you as members, former members of Congress
recently retired, the reality is that if the six of you go and sit down with various people
in Congress, not to expect that they're going to change overnight and say oh look, let's
have a hearing on this and expose it to our people, but the fact that you have come to
discover just this week so much more than you ever knew was going on, that you are experts
at trying to share this information with people in your regions of the country and we have
from all different parts of the country, from Alaska to California to other states of our
country, right, in the south of our country and in the midwest of our country, we can,
if you will reach out and try to talk with your people in your own districts about this
issue to take upon yourself that risk of the potential ridicule, the potential criticism,
the question you've been asking yourself, all of you, what am I going to do now? What
am I going to do now that I have left the Congress? Am I going to continue to represent
the people in my district? Am I going to attempt to educate them? Because if you have come
to the same conclusion that I came to when I was given the privilege of representing
Dr. John Mack, if you've come to the same conclusion that I have, this is one of the
most important issues that you've ever encountered in your life and you are the most skilled
people to go and share this with your own constituency and reach out and help us. That's
what we're asking for you to do.
Thank you for your statement, Mr. Chan. We'll now begin the questioning of our witnesses
and we're going to change the order. We're going to start with Dr. Bookman and we're
just going to work our way down this way.
Mr. Dolan, we've had this conversation before and I think it might be helpful to the committee
too. How many crashes do you find credible, roughly?
I've never bothered to tally them up. There are a couple of very good book studies that
have been done, one by a gentleman who's here, Dr. Kevin Randle, another by Ryan Wood.
How many do your colleagues generally, as you look at their materials, have you concluded?
I don't think 10 would be outrageous.
Maybe 10 craft have been recovered, 10 crashes. Let's talk about those 10. We assume that
we're not the most enlightened, caring, loving folk in the galaxy, I gather. Is there any
evidence that the colleagues of these crashed extraterrestrials have come looking for them
or attempted to recover their crash technology or their brothers and sisters who might have
been held in captivity, no matter how comfortable here?
All we're dealing with are leaks and more leaks and stories and claims. It would not
be illogical. There have been claims that have been made proving these, getting corroboration
is another story.
Thank you.
Yes, Representative Willsies.
Thank you. I think we should shorten this as best we can, except for the Honorable Paul
Heller. One thing I'd like to say to Paul Heller is, I think we know the answer about
who knows about this, when you two guys brought it up. I think Mr. Heller answered it for
us. It's the three sisters. I mean, they know of the industrial complexes, the oil cabal,
the banking cabal. They know. They've been controlling this for a long time. We know
they know, and we know they've been controlling it, so our question is now, what do we do
about it? I don't think it does a lot of good to go out and insult the people that are going
to have to do something about it, but we can do more than we're doing. We have to get money
out of politics, one. I don't mean control the press, what they can see. We have to expand
the press so that three or five corporations don't own the communications in our country.
We have to do something about our education system so that our students graduate knowing
how to question, staying in school in the first place, but they have to learn how to
question. They have to learn how to analyze. They have to make decisions that are in their
own best interests, not in the best interests of the top 1% of the wealthiest people in
this country. We have to have economic justice. I mean, there's so much that we have to do
in this country. If we had a country that was not based on money and had a press that
would speak truth to power and uneducated public, we'd be demanding and wanting to hear
everything that I heard this week from all of you. It isn't there, it isn't happening,
and we just do, I mean, we have so much work to do. I mean, and then the question of, well,
my question is, what would it look like, why would it be upsetting to get this information
out? What does upsetting information look like?
Well, Ms. Wilsey, if I might have something to say on that. I had a conversation with
a gentleman who I will just say is of absolutely impeccable credentials who told me of his
personal knowledge of a briefing that was given to President Jimmy Carter back in June
of 1977 on exactly this matter. Now, he doesn't know the details of what was said, but he
does know that it was a briefing about the extraterrestrial presence. This was in June
of 1977, the beginning of his first year. And at the end of that meeting, the President
was seen with his head in his hands, elbows on the desk, and weeping or deeply upset.
Something was told to him that was very upsetting. I asked this individual if he had any idea
what it was. He did not bother to speculate. But I will say that I have another gentleman
who was a senior cabinet member in the first Reagan administration, who similarly told
of being taken for several weeks after he got his job to an underground facility to
receive a briefing and was deeply upset because, as he said to a trusted family member, I have
a daughter and I am terrified for her. So there is something going on in which this
phenomenon is either threatening or we might speculate beyond the control of the political
powers that are officially representing us. Well, it is beyond control. It is the three
sisters that are running it. So thank you. Thank you. And let's go to a representative
from Maryland. Thank you very much. I want to, for a few
moments dwell a bit on a problem that was mentioned by both Mr. Hillier and Dr. Bookman.
That is the constitutional issue here. For the moment, we are the undisputed economic
and military superpower in the world. We are a bit less than 5% of the world's population.
We are about one person out of 22 in the world. And we have just about, we represent about
a fourth of the world's economy, which means we have about a fourth of all the good things
in the world. How come? How come? We no longer have the best work ethic in the world. All
you have to do is drive around and watch for people bending their back and sweating and
working. You won't see very many white faces. You don't see very many black faces. You see
Hispanic faces. We no longer have the most respect for the nuclear family. This year,
almost half our babies will be born out of wedlock. We no longer have the most respect
for technical education. This year, the Chinese will graduate seven times as many engineering
students as we graduate. How is it then that we are so darn fortunate that we are the undisputed
economic and military superpower in the world? I think it's because of our enormous respect.
And we have a fourth of all the good things in the world. I think it's our enormous respect
for civil liberties. There's no other constitution. There's no other bill of rights to protect
civil liberties like ours. And I think, by the way, you've mentioned it, gentlemen. We
are not a democracy. We are a democratic process. But we are a republic, Benjamin Franklin asked.
There's a fundamental difference there. There's a fundamental difference there. I'm very concerned
that because our government today so easily ignores the constitution to do what they think
are good things, that tomorrow, like some of the functions of our government that I think
are extra constitutional, if not unconstitutional, like ignoring the First Amendment requirement
that the citizens have a right to petition the government for a redress of grievances.
And there's a grievance that there's not been a hearing on this for a very long time.
If the government can ignore the constitution to be good things today, tomorrow they can
ignore the constitution to do bad things. Other countries have done it.
When my ex-chief of staff, who is now my colleague, called me and asked me if I was interested
in this and warned me that there was a big probability that a lot of people would relegate
me to the lunatic fringe for coming here. I told her that the primary reason that I
would come was that there's a serious constitutional issue here. The citizens have a right for
their government to tell them what's going on here. And I want to thank both of you for
bringing up this constitutional issue because I think it is a very serious one. A government
which ignores the constitution to do good things today, what they think are good things
today, can ignore the constitution to do bad things tomorrow because it will rationalize
that they are good things tomorrow. So thank you very much for your shared concern of this
issue.
[Applause]
Senator, we've got five minutes for questions. You'll have five minutes for questions and
then whatever time afterwards we'll start with you on closing states.
What I'd like to do is ask Minister Heller, we all talk about the problem. In fact, that's
all I hear is defining the problem. We've got to think in terms of solutions. What's
your solution to the problem?
You have got problems. Wall Street runs your economy. And the military, if you elect a
president who is presumably commander in chief of the armed forces, but he's not clear to
know what the troops in his command are actually doing. So I think, you know, there are some
big problems. But I think Congress ultimately has the key to both the future of the United
States and of the world. And this is what bothers me because they're not exercising
their power to change the things that have to be changed. But if you'll indulge me, I'd
like to read two pages from advice from the extraterrestrials. And I think they've got
a lot of good advice because they know what's going on more than we do sometimes. This is
a quote from Jim Sparks, who was probably the most abducted of all the people who have
been abducted. And he was taken away one night late on. He'd been abducted dozens of times
before that. And he said, I found myself standing in that abandoned carnival park, clearheaded
and fully conscious. There were those creatures again. And I could see that their holograms
of human faces were cast over their faces to disguise their true appearance and make
me feel less apprehensive. I noticed that each alien seemed to be concentrating and
communicating or transmitting its thoughts to the creature to my left. They seemed to
be of like mind as though combining their consciousness into one telepathic voice. They
continue. And now this is quoting the ETs. There are some things you need to understand.
Yes, it's true that we have been in contact with your government and heads of power. It
is also true that agreements have been made and kept secret from your people. It is also
true that in the past some of your people have lost their lives or have been badly hurt
to protect the secret. Our hands had no part in this. We contacted your leaders because
your planet is in grave trouble. Your leaders said the vast majority of your population
wasn't ready for anything like us yet. So we made time agreements with your leaders
as to when your people would be made aware of our presence. That part of the agreement
has not at all been kept. It was also agreed that in the meantime, steps would be taken
to correct the environmental conditions of your planet with our advice and technology.
We say "advice" because we respect the fact that this is your planet, not ours. They also
broke that agreement. This is Jim now. I felt an awful wave of emotion from them, the feeling
of abandonment. To feel any emotion from them at all was amazing, but this was quite overwhelming.
You aren't giving up on us, are you? I asked. There was a long silent pause, and I received
the transmitted feeling of tremendous loss. Well, are you? I asked. No. I felt an immediate
sense of relief straight from my own emotions. But then the extraterrestrials again, your
air, your water are contaminated. Your forests, jungles, trees and plant life are dying. There
are several breaks in your food chain. You have an overwhelming amount of nuclear and
biological weapons, which include nuclear and biological contamination. Your planet
is overpopulated. Warning, it is almost to the point of being too late, unless your people
act. There are better ways of deriving energy and food needs without causing your planet
any damage. Those in power are aware of this and have the capability of putting these methods
into worldwide use. I let this digest for a moment. I definitely had the feeling that
these creatures are speaking as one. Then I asked, why aren't we doing that now? Silence.
I was willing to wait. I had come a long way to be treated like this by them to have this
kind of meeting. Apparently I had earned their respect and trust. The best part was that
I was getting direct truthful answers to my questions. I decided that I would milk this
rare situation to its fullest, asking as many questions as I could get away with, even personal
ones. I repeated my question and they answered. Those in power view it as a military and security
threat. That upset me. You mean to tell me that the people in power have the ability
to save and better the planet and they aren't doing it? Amnesty. What do you mean? Complete
amnesty to those in power, governments and leaders who have been suppressing the truth,
that they can't be held liable for any past wrong deeds. It is the only way these leaders
can come forward with the truth. It is necessary that you do this in order to work together
and survive.
I think that's wonderful advice straight from the ECPS wheels. I think Congress should exercise
its power. I know that they've got some job owning, but they have the ultimate power.
They could say to the junta, "We want you to do this. We'll give you amnesty, protection.
We want you to do this and you're going to do it. If you don't, we'll cut your funding
off except for salaries and wages until you do do it." Because it's in the national interest
and it's in the world interest. We want to know what's going on and specifically we want
the energy sources to put into effect to save the world before it's too darn late.
Thank you very much. We'll start the closing statements by Senator -- well, is there a
--
As much as you want.
Yeah, you get your closing statement.
Don't ever say that to me. I filibuster.
I should have warned Dr. Buckman about that, but anyway, go ahead.
I'll be reasonable. I'll put it that way.
First off, if I've sounded angry, I apologize for that, but there's a reason. I am angry,
very angry, but I really want to point out that I love my country. I'm very critical
of it because it needs to be criticized heavily. I consider myself a patriot, but I don't buy
into -- but first and foremost, and I used to end a lot of my speeches and I lasted for
12 years, I am a citizen of the planet first and American second, and my priorities are
on that way. Make no mistake about that.
Now, when we're analyzing the problem, whether it's the extraterrestrial situation issue
or the 9/11 issue, which of course ginned up the ability of the crazies to really go
after the world, we have to start and be a little humble and say, hey, those of us that
have held office for a period of time, it's during that period of time that things have
gone to hell, and when people say, well, we ought to take back our country, we never had
our country, if you read the Constitution, it was passed in '87 and '89, the first -- we
were putting in slavery for infinity, and if you look at -- and those of you that have
this brochure, you'll look at all of our forebears that said the people should have the right
to change their government, and that's based upon the Declaration of Independence where
all human beings are created equal. Well, 12 years later, they're in Philadelphia,
and they're not creating all human beings equal. What they're doing is they're making
a distinction that white males are the only equal ones, and if you have enough property,
the rest, and so those who get married to the Constitution, they like to rip the Constitution
apart, and then when you say about, you know, obeying the Constitution, after the Civil
War amendments, which really is the only improvement made in the Constitution of size because it
expanded the franchise, and if you look at the amendments, the rest of it are just housekeeping,
and so from the Civil War on, we had 90 years where, what, 12, 13 states were in total violation
of the Constitution of the United States, and nobody gave a darn about it, and the political
parties were all part of the conspiracy. So when you advance from there to here and
look around and see how our scientific advancement has been so explosive, and we are stuck in
a system, a structure of governance that's 250 years old that is totally irrelevant to
dealing with our problems that we face today, and then so we look at, say, oh, we're going
to go to the Congress. I got to tell you, I've said that earlier in the week. It's a
dead letter, and hold your breath. It's never going to happen, and it's not that I'm demeaning
the Congress. I've been there, and I'll tell you that they don't have the power that you
think they have. I don't want to engage in anything. I respect your views, but I just
want to tell you that the problem, you have to come to some kind of a search internally
with some humility and say, maybe, just maybe, our structure of governance is deficient,
is deficient. We don't have a democracy, never had it. What we have is representative government.
That's what came out of the Age of Enlightenment, was representative government, where the majority
of the people give their power away to a small minority, and that small minority, and you
want to know what happened, $4 billion was spent in the last election in our government,
the Congress, the executive, the bureaucracy, the judiciary. They are owned, locked, stocked,
and barreled by the Wall Street, the military industrial complex, and all the special interests
that we find abroad. Then when you see what's going on with NATO is nothing but the militarization,
the globalization of the military industrial complex. That's what's going on. I referred
to a study where it showed that 1,300 corporations with interlocking directorates and family
ties own 60% of the wealth of the world. Then you've gone through the litany of the Bilderberg
group and all of that group. Sure, they do what's natural to them. They've got power,
and they're clever enough to keep it and work for it. Our task is to look at the structure
of why we're failing as human beings. I say all of us, because we've had testimony replete
of people in the military who are supposed to be courageous and prepared to charge up
the hill, that they defer to authority that silences them. If you reason it out, it doesn't
make any sense that they have to keep secrets like that. I had to make that decision in
the Senate and put myself at risk when releasing the Pentagon papers. Those were top secret
documents. The rest of the Congress was stymied like little kids in school that you could
go read it, but you couldn't take any notes. They tried to impeach me, and I was saved
by one person, Mike Mansfield. He had such power in the Senate. He stepped before a delegation
led by Gerald Ford, brought it with Hugh Scott, went to visit him and said, "Well, we've
got to deal with this Gravel for what he's done," and Mansfield turned to him, sucking
on his pipe. He says, "He's done nothing that I know of," and they walked right out.
That was the end of the story. That saved my career. When I went to see Mansfield, and
I get emotional about it, because what he turned to me says, "Mike, if I had had your
courage, I would have done the same thing," but stop and think what I did. The whole Congress
had bought into the secrecy of these documents, and I had turned it all over and made the
Supreme Court moot and put to shame the newspapers that were now afraid to do it, and the issue
with the Supreme Court. Our government, representative government, is designed to keep the people
in civic adolescence. That's what it's designed. What is adolescence? "Oh, I want that, but
I don't want to pay any taxes. I want that, but I don't want to pay any taxes." That's
adolescent behavior. Now, how do we bring the people to adulthood, civic adulthood?
We do it the way we bring our children up. We give our children responsibility as they
age, and then they come to adulthood. It's taking responsibility, but when you have a
structure of government that doesn't permit the people to take responsibility, you guarantee
the continuation of civic adolescence. What I've tried to do with this work, and this
represents the last 25 years of my public life, and it will continue until the day I
die, and that is that the answer is the people. It's not your leaders. Don't trust your leaders.
It's the people. There's only two venues for change. One is the government, wherein structurally
the problem exists, and the other is the people. The government won't, but the people can't
because they give their power away. I'll close on one quote which says it all, and that
is very simple. It's a quote from 2,000 years ago. Marcus Cicero defined freedom as participation
in power. You will never, never see fundamental change in our society or global society until
the power can be relegated to the people directly. It's just that simple. I make that as a prediction.
I've resigned myself that I'll keep working, but I won't see this in my lifetime. Won't
see it in my lifetime, but someday people are going to wake up and say, "Hey, what's
so worrisome about empowering the people to be able to do what?" When Cicero says freedom
is power, is participation in power, what is the central power of all governments, whether
tyrannies or democracy or republics? It's the ability to make laws that stand outside
of ourselves and that we're supposed to obey them. At this point in time, only representatives
make laws, and these representatives de facto are controlled by these forces beyond our
control because they control society. The answer is to find a way to empower people
to be able to make laws. Therefore, they will have the power to do away with the secrecy
in government. Does it surprise you that 50% of the people don't even care about government?
This is not Einstein's theory. Well, it is Einstein's theory. He said that to repeat
over and over again something that doesn't work is the definition of insanity. That's
a great theory. We vote for Democrats, nothing really happens. We vote for Republicans, nothing
really happens. We go to Britain, we see one government, that government, nothing really
happens to advance the needs of the human race. You can only come to one conclusion
that the answer is not with the elites. They manipulate our elections. Mind you, I raise
money from special sources to run for office, and I manipulate my constituency. I do that.
I'm sure any successful politician has done that, is to manipulate the constituency for
your thinking. To think that we in elective office want a turnout of voters, hell no.
We want a turnout of our voters, not the general voters. The whole structure of representative
government is very deficient. Let me lead with this, that I have personally unreserved
faith in the people. If you don't have faith in the people, what do you have faith in?
The leaders, and that's exactly where we're at today. If you want to see this issue of
being able to maturely, and I don't think we have close to the maturity to deal with
the extraterrestrials. We're told, and I'll accept that, that we have the scientific ability
to send ET home. Well, it's being sequestered away from the people, and that's a tragedy
because there's a lot more out there that could benefit the human race, but we can't
get our hands on it because we don't have the structure of governance to be able to
go at it. Let me close on it. If those of you that don't have this, you can go to our
website, National Citizens Initiative for Democracy. Hopefully, it won't succeed in my lifetime,
but it is my contribution and a legacy. Forget the Pentagon Papers, forget the nuclear critique,
forget the end of the draft. This is the contribution that I think is worthwhile, and I won't live
to see it. Thank you very much. If you will get in your car, and it'll be
a little more spectacular in the wintertime because the air is thinner and it holds less
moisture, and if you will drive out of the city away from the lights and away from the
air pollution, and you drive up a mountain several thousand feet, you don't have to go
very far to do that. A hundred miles in West Virginia will do it, and on a cloudless winter
night you look up into the sky. You will just be astounded at the Milky Way. Wow, it looks
like they took a whitewash brush across the sky. There are so darn many stars there, more
than a billion. And then when you recognize that our star is a pretty mediocre star in
this galaxy of the Milky Way, and then when you know that there are probably a billion
other galaxies this size. You know, as a scientist, there just has to be another sun out there,
another star, and another planet that has characteristics appropriate for the development
of life. And I think you have to be very arrogant and very presumptive to believe that we're
the only civilization in the universe, and the most advanced civilization. Wow, we're
still killing each other in stupid wars, and not all that long ago, I'm Anglo-Saxon, German,
and my forebears were wearing skins in a stone age running around Europe. As I mentioned
earlier when my chief of staff, with whom I now work, said that I was invited to come
here and warn me that you might be ridiculed for it, I told her that I was going to come
because of the constitutional issue for no other, which I mentioned. Because if your
government can rationalize that it's okay to deny you this hearing for your good, tomorrow
they can be doing a lot of things that are very hurtful to you, because in the grand
scheme of things, they will rationalize that it's for your good. Thank you very much, those
of you who organized this. I've really been privileged to be here. I'm honored that you
invited me to come. And thank you to the witnesses. And I think back through these five days and
the witnesses have come, some of them at considerable personal price. And a special thanks to those
who have borne this secret for 40, 50 years, and now near their deathbed, come forward
so that we can know. I ask myself why this cloak of secrecy? Clearly there is a cloak
of secrecy. And I ask myself why. My wife says that I'm the eternal optimist. And I'd
like to think the best of everybody until proven different. And so I want to believe
that those who made decisions were patriotic Americans, believing that at the time they
made the decision which was in the best interest of their country. This was just a few years
after the War of the Worlds thing where the East Coast was panicked when they thought
we were being invaded by extraterrestrials. And that was one concern that I think they
must have had that was fairly recent in their memory. Another concern would be, gee, there
really is some advanced technology here, isn't there? And wouldn't it be tragic if the Soviets
had that rather than us or shared it with us? And so I think for these two reasons they
could very well have rationalized it. And that decision was made very early. Apparently
it may have gone clear to the office of the president because within a few hours after
they issued that press release that said that a flying saucer had crashed, they came with
this ridiculous press release saying, gee, it was just a balloon. We goofed. But they
did send what they found to Wright Field and they did send a number of people out to vacuum
the area for several days. These three things alone tell me that the Air Force knows that
they're not telling us the truth. I hope that after 60-odd years of known incidents
after the Soviet Union has gone that these two justifications they recognized are no
longer valid and that they might come and tell the American people there is something
out there that we can't explain. And we're sorry that for all these years that we rationalized
that it was the national interest of our country to keep this from you. I may be the eternal
optimist but I'd like to thank the best of people. Again, thank you so very much for
putting this on. Thank you for honoring me to be a part of it. Thank you.
I certainly want to thank everybody that's been involved in this whole operation this
week and I just want to say how grateful I am for being contacted and asked to participate
and how glad I am that I accepted this opportunity to be on this panel. But I want to focus my
closing statement and keep it very short on the witnesses. I still can't believe the quality
of the witnesses that we've seen this week has been about 40, about 40. This is meant
as a total compliment. I can't, when I contemplated coming here to Washington for this, I certainly
couldn't imagine that you could assemble in one conference that number of people with
that level of capability, competence, commitment, and intelligence. The witnesses are far better
than I think anyone of us had a right to expect when we accepted this. And maybe it's because
I don't know enough about ufology. And Congressman, there is five more behind every one of those
40 that can come forward just as strong. I'm starting to have no doubt about that at all
after hearing just a small sampling of pilots and controllers and people on the ground that
have seen things and witnessed things. And the integrity and believability, honesty,
and clear thought of each of these testimonies was something to behold. I have to say that.
I'm just very impressed on that. And I'm going to conclude the remarks by saying to all of
the witnesses and each and every one witness, if you're a researcher, you keep on researching
and redouble those research efforts. If you're someone in the media that's trying to understand
this and help promote it, work harder at it. And if, I mean, you're doing a good job, don't
get me wrong, but I just want you to redouble this. Because, you know, if it's true, I've
announced before I even came here that I believe in extraterrestrial life. And that was from
a religious standpoint. So I've been focusing on scientific evidence of it. And let me just
say this. I'm like, sorry the name slips through me, but the person that used to be the minister
of, or in the Ministry of Defense, Nick Pope. I'm like Dick Pope. I haven't come to a definite
scientific conclusion on that question. But I hope in the short lifetime I have left,
I can, based on science. And if you researchers will redouble the efforts and if anybody that
can help fund and resource this kind of effort can get committed and get going, because hey,
I can tell you this must have cost some real money, what you've done here. And that's a
compliment to the fundraising skill that you obviously all have that have been involved.
So I'd just like to end with this final sentence. Keep working hard. Use this as just kind of
a springboard to redoubling your efforts. Thank you very much.
Well, I want to thank my colleagues and thanks for putting this group of six together. It
could not have been better balanced. It was balanced politically. It was balanced gender-wise,
absolutely. And it was balanced with our beliefs. And it's so clear. People say we don't get
along. We get along. And when you take the politics out of it, it makes it a lot easier.
And I will say what we say in the Congress when we want to save time, is that I echo
our chairman's viewpoint on the witnesses. He said it perfectly. The knowledge, the experience,
and the integrity of this group of witnesses made it such an important week for me and
I know for many others. Actually, with this amazing group of witnesses that we heard,
and as we talked about this subject, it made it absolutely impossible for me to remain
a skeptic. But I don't believe that it's about -- I don't believe it's about belief.
I believe this whole situation is about information. And the existence of UFOs and ETs is becoming
accepted worldwide. And the information we received was so important to support that
and defend it. But it's time for our government, the U.S. government, to come to the party.
It's time for our government to declassify and disclose what they know. And it is time
that they trust the people of this country, that they can handle this information, whatever
they think we can't handle, because they are dead wrong and it's going to get in the way
of the get-along of this nation we live in. So we're not living in a flat-earth society.
We know it, and it's time that our government realizes it, as well, and that they make it
possible for us to go forward. Because if they don't, I agree that the general public
will. And I thank you again for making this all possible. Thank you.
Absolutely blessed to have been given the opportunity to fill Congresswoman Huli's seat
when she left earlier today. I'd like to echo what Congressman Cook said about the heroic
actions of the witnesses who came here this week. And what Congressman Bartlett said about
those brilliant stars under that winter night in West Virginia. But what I'm here to suggest
is that we have stars who've shone just as brightly this week and other human beings
who are here who were just as heroic. And I'd like to share a little bit about that.
I shared my gratitude for Congressman Kilpatrick, who was the first to say, "Yeah, I'll do it."
But there's other stories around that I'd like to share that I'd like everyone in the
room to be aware of as well. Just before I do that, though, I'd also like to make a call-out
to those watching this on the Internet stream, or those who might be in the room, or those
who might see it in the weeks, months, years to come, who have the opportunity to be heroic,
who do know about this, who have evidence, who could testify, who live perhaps in fear.
And my call-out to you is to do what these six members of Congress have done, which is
to be heroic, to stand up and recognize an allegiance, if not to the Constitution, then
to your fellow men on this planet, men and women on the planet, to share what you know
to be true about this issue. Congressman Bartlett has been commuting two and a half hours every
morning to be here, two and a half hours back to his farm in Virginia. He's 86 years old.
[applause] Sir, you're a hero to me. Your commitment
to our Constitution and the principles of liberty that it embodies, and yes, Senator
Gravel's right, it never embodied them perfectly, but it was a huge advance in the history of
humanity on this planet to grant liberty to the people, to see the government not as the
giver of rights, but as of rights being self-evident and inalienable, inalienable for each individual.
Your commitment to that is heroic. Congressman Woolsey, who's sitting next to me right now,
authored legislation to protect whistleblowers that this government, this Congress, refused
to pass. And we've been, if you haven't noticed, attacking whistleblowers for at least the
last 12 years at an ever-increasing rate. It's unconstitutional. It's anti-liberty.
It's criminal. And she and I have partnered on bringing greater freedom to other social
organizations and inclusiveness in other battles not related to this issue. I mentioned Carolyn
being first earlier, and I want to say how great a gift that was to all of us putting
this together. Again, somebody had to be first. Senator Gravel, when I called him, said, "Do
you mind if I quote you on this and share a private phone call for a bit, Senator, in
the world of full disclosure?" He said, "How much money are you offering again? God damn
it, I usually do these things for free, and this is the first time I can't go. My wife
and I just made plans to be on a cruise on the Danube at that time, and he changed his
vacation plans to be here." Canceled his vacation. Very few people in this room know, but just
this past Sunday, Congresswoman Hooley was in the hotel, the Washington Plaza sobbing
because she had just learned her sister had died a couple of days earlier in California,
and she'd had the opportunity to say goodbye to her sister, but she was devastated, and
she came here anyway. That's a hero to all of us. Then one more, and I'll conclude, but
I think it's fair to say as a fairly hardcore libertarian, I've had a seething contempt
for most of Congress, for most of my life. I'm currently serving as the chair of the
National Libertarian Party's platform committee, and thinking about these issues of how do
we save what was once the land of the free and the home of the brave, and has become
the land of the bailed out and the home of the terrorized by the tyranny of its government.
And I've fallen in love with Congress this week. You all have been learning about UFOs.
I've been learning about the great character of the men and women who actually do serve
this nation, and if you're representatives of what's still there, even a portion of it,
all hope is not lost. Merrill Cook invited me to come down and brief him. He lives about
a half hour from my home in Park City, and when I got there I discovered that he's the
full-time caretaker for the love of his life, Camille, and he has every door of his house
locked from the inside out so that she doesn't wander off. She's suffering from Alzheimer's.
And his one concern before he agreed to be here was, "If I come, would it be possible
for my wife to be in the audience where I could see her so that I know she's okay, because
I'll never put her in an institution? She's the love of my life, but I need to have her
in a seat where I can see her with someone sitting next to her so I can focus on the
testimony. And sir, if I could love my wife half as much as I've seen you as an example
of love to yours, I'll be okay." You, sir, are a hero as well.
First of all, I would like to thank the panel. You'll be interested to know that I had considerable
empathy with you to see all of that information being thrown at you so fast, and on a subject
which was completely foreign to you. And you did a remarkable job of accepting it, adjusting
it and being, in effect, transformed by it. And how I wish that more people would be in
that position so that we could really get the word out and get the kind of action that
we dream of. But as the Senator says, it may be just a dream, but I hope not, because time
is running out. So thank you very much, every one of you. You are great, and we appreciate
what you have done. And just hope, Mr. Chairman, that you too all redouble your effort when
you go out to try and influence people to expose themselves to this kind of information
so that they too may understand. And the witnesses, I must say, I agree with everything that's
been said about them. I have never seen anything like it in my life. Just absolutely transfixed.
I've seen more heroes in five days than I've seen ever before in my life, except perhaps
on VE Day or something. But just wonderful people who are willing to stick their necks
out because they are deeply, deeply committed in the search of truth. And that's what we've
got to do. I hesitate to mention names because every single one of them should be singled
up. I was particularly thankful this morning to both Richard and Linda that they got us
into some of the things that we hadn't been in before. And I will never forget Colonel
French admitting that his job was to invent the excuses for the UFOs and that he designated
a lot of them as swamp gas. We all knew that the swamp gas and the plasma and the balloons
and all this sort of stuff was you know what. But to have him say so was -- but he said
something else that I think that is even more memorable to me. And that is never put weapons
in space. We adhere to the space treaty. Google the space treaty and listen to Carol Ross
and on the reasons why we should have a common access to the space, everybody. And not try
to see if we can outwit other people in being the first to spend a lot of money putting
weapons in space. And I feel very strongly on that. It's an issue which I have been involved
in for a long while and which I will continue to support. And final word is Bob Sallis I
also remember because he summed up the situation in one classic sentence. It's power and greed.
It's not national security. That's what I believe.
And Paul mentioned heroes. Let me introduce one now. Jesse, do you have a few words to
say before we leave?
Well, I have a few words. I'll keep these remarks short because everything has already
been said really. But I do want to express my appreciation and honor in presenting my
story to this panel.
Since 1947, I have known that we're not alone in this universe. Because based on the material
I saw that my dad brought in from the desert, I realized this is not a human manufacture.
So if we didn't make it, it means somebody else did. And when you look out at the night
stars, night sky there in New Mexico, you realize this beautiful place that we live
in is called the universe, or our galaxy. As a matter of fact, there's 10 of the 22nd
power stars in the known galaxy, which equates the number of grains of sand on the beaches
of the earth. And to say that only one grain of sand out of that multitude has sentient
life like us around it is just begging the question there. Because someone once said
very truthfully that if we're the only ones here, there's an awful lot of wasted space
out there.
So anyway, I started thinking about this. People ask me, "How does this affect my religion,
my belief in God?" Well, I believe in the intelligent design. Because if in the very
beginning at the Big Bang, when things were created, if the parameters were changed just
ever so slightly, like the rate of expansion of the universe, or the charge on the proton,
or the electron, or the masses thereof, had that been off by 1 trillion from what it turned
out to be, we wouldn't be here, nor would our cousins from outer space be here too.
And I, you know, I'll give you my philosophy. I think we're all related. People of earth,
people of star status, you know, wherever they come from, we're all related to them.
Because in the very beginning when the Big Bang occurred, there's something called quantum
entanglement that occurred. And Einstein calls this spooky action at a distance, but that
means that all particles created in the Big Bang are related to each other. One example
is where they would take two matched particles, send one of them, could be light years away,
but you'd make one change and one, the other one changes correspondingly instantly. Like
there's faster than light communication.
So again, we're all related, we're in this universe, and we have a lot of cousins out
there.
[Applause]